<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Elarion (Playersafe)]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>lib\media\favicon.png</url><title>Elarion (Playersafe)</title><link/></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 06:29:02 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="lib\rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 06:29:02 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator/><item><title><![CDATA[The Dawnward Cane]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
“She gave her breath to the wind, her warmth to the sun, her will to the mountain—and her heart to the staff.”
<br><br><br>
<br>The staff is roughly six feet tall, but hovers half an inch above the ground, never fully touching it.  
<br>Its core is white ashwood, but it has been infused with radiant crystal, causing it to shimmer faintly with light that changes hue with alignment proximity.  
<br>Around the head of the staff spiral three golden rings, which move slowly and silently in orbit—each one etched with unreadable celestial script.  
<br>A faint chime rings from the staff when evil draws near, barely audible over the hum of the barrier.
<br><br><br>
<br>The staff was crafted not by hands, but by Saint Vivi herself, through an act of divine transmutation at the moment she invoked the barrier.  
<br>It is said the wood came from the First Tree of the mountain pass, and the light from a fallen star.  
<br>When Vivi cast the spell that formed the barrier, she poured her soul into the staff, causing her body to collapse and the artifact to root itself into the sanctum floor.
<br><br><br>ᚠ ᛗᚺᛃ ᚠᛇᛇᚲᛠ ᚲᛁᛠ ᛋᛚᛖᛉ ᛈᛈᛁᛠᚲ ᚢᚷ ᛃᚦᛡᚦᚠᛗᛚ ᚢᛉ ᛇᛡᛃᛃᛡ ᚦᛒᛏᛡᛠᛡᛚᛚᛃᛋᛒ ᚺᚺ ᚹᛉᛡ ᛃᛏᛞᚨᛈᛁᛉᛞ ᛞᚹ ᛖᚾᛈᚨᛝᚢᛃᚺᛉ ᛖᛇᛖᛏᛈ ᛗᛡᛖᛞᚾᚱᛚᚱᚱᛏ ᛋᚠᛃᛚᚾᚠᛃᛞᛃᛚᚱᛚᚦᚷ<br>
ᛡ ᛠᛞ ᛃᚨᚾᛗ ᛋᚾᛝᛝᚦᚺᚹᛡᛡᚠᛝᛠᛚᚾᛃᛟᛡ ᚹᚢᚢᚠᛖ ᛈᚱᛟᚷᚨᚦᛏᚾᛇ ᛒᚲᚠᛠᛞᚢᛒᚲᛁᚱᛗᛡᚠᛏᛠᛇ ᛚᛡᛇᛏᛈ ᚾᚷᛚᚲᚹᛒᛈ ᛖᚢᚹᚲ ᛁᚱᛁ ᛃᚦᛞᛠᛁ ᛠᚺᛝᛁᛁ ᛃᛈᛝᛃ ᚠᛖᛠᛞᚦᚹᚦ ᛞᛇᛉᛟᚷᛏᚲ ᛏᛡᚹ ᛇᛝᚷᛃᛖᛃᛋᛠᚦᛖ ᛡᚺ ᛗ ᛁᚱᚷᛋᚲᛞᛇ ᛉᛋᛃᛝᛁ ᛉᚠ ᛋᚹᛟ ᚱᚷᛡᛝᚲᚲᛝ ᚢᛗᛈᛞᚲ<br>
ᛡ ᚷᛉ ᛟᚦ ᛞᚹᛒᚢ ᛋᚾᚦ ᚠᚢᛉᚠᚹ ᛞᛝ ᛝᛚᛏᛡᛚᛖᛉᛇ ᛃ ᚱᛟᚦᛚᚲᛈᚹᛗᚹᚢᚱᛠᛏ ᚹᛝᚾᚷᚷ ᚢᛖᛗᛉ ᛉᛈᚲᚨᛡ ᛚᛠᚷᛁ ᚱᛗᚢ ᛚᚷᛖᛗ ᛉᚷᚷᛁᛇᚠᛝ ᛖᚨᚠᚨᛒᛠ ᚱᚠᛡᚨ ᛝᚠᚠᛁ ᚢᛁᛁᚺᛖᛝᛞ]]></description><link>one-off-pages\the-dawnward-cane.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">One off pages/The Dawnward Cane.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 06:28:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[House Dravakar]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
“By fire, we rose.”
<br><br><br>House Dravakar is the oldest and most feared noble house in the <a data-href="Arken Dominion" href="kingdoms\arken-dominion.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Arken Dominion</a>. Its name is synonymous with both the glory of conquest and the price of hubris. Descended from the original bloodline that led the hunt against the dragons, the Dravakars now rule from the Ember Throne, a blackstone dais embedded with molten crystal, perpetually surrounded by flowing lava.<br>They are the only house to bear the true curse of the dying red dragon whose breath melted the Dominion’s capital into its current volcanic state. Though the curse disfigured many and twisted the land, the Dravakars embraced it as divine judgment—and forged themselves anew.<br><br><br>
<br>Many members of House Dravakar exhibit draconic mutations: glowing ember-like veins, eyes that flicker like flame, or scorched, scale-like skin  
<br>They wear armor forged from heat-bound obsidian and dragonbone, often etched with infernal script or fire-glyphs  
<br>Their voices carry an unnatural weight, and it’s said the air shakes slightly around them when they are angry  
<br><br><br>
<br>The Ember Throne is always occupied by a Dravakar; they serve as the Dominion’s ultimate rulers, both politically and spiritually  
<br>They command not only armies but the Flamebound Court—an elite cadre of fire-mages, executioners, and priests who maintain the cursed flame at the heart of the capital  
<br>No law passes without their mark. No rebellion begins without first fearing their gaze  
<br><br><br>
<br>House Dravakar believes in burning away weakness—in themselves, in others, in the world  
<br>They view their curse as both a punishment and a blessing, proof of their unique destiny  
<br>Children of the house undergo ritual trials of flame at age 10. Those who survive are named. Those who fail are forgotten  
<br>The eldest Dravakars teach that the curse will only be lifted when the Dominion surpasses the dragons in all things—in magic, power, and legacy  
<br><br><br>Highlord Kavalh Dravakar, the Flame-Ordained King  <br>
<br>A brooding, iron-handed monarch with half his face encased in blackened crystal  
<br>Rumored to sleep atop molten stone, communing with something ancient that lives beneath the capital  
]]></description><link>houses\arken\house-dravakar.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Houses/Arken/House Dravakar.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 20:25:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[House Ferrosyn]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
“The forge obeys the hand that dares.”
<br><br><br>House Ferrosyn is the industrial engine of the Arken Dominion—pioneers of arcane machinery, molten metallurgy, and volatile innovation. They possess no ancient bloodline magic, no divine favor—only relentless experimentation and ambition born in fire.<br>Where others seek mastery, Ferrosyn seeks momentum. Their workshops never sleep. Their prototypes often explode. But when one works, it changes the battlefield, the market, or the Dominion itself.<br><br><br>Tovar Ferrosyn<br>
Lord of Sparks<br>
House leader and director of the Ember Crucible—Ferrosyn’s largest and most dangerous forge-facility.<br>
<br>Created the Dominion’s first lava-powered mobile siege engine, “<a data-href="Red Howl" href="one-off-pages\red-howl.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Red Howl</a>.”  
<br>Keeps a prosthetic arm powered by combustion glyphs and cooled by gemstone valves.
<br><br><br>A black-iron spire built atop a river of lava, filled with scaffolding, steam-pipes, and clangor.<br>
<br>Run by layered guilds, overseen by Tovar’s forge-council.  
<br>Features constant experimental trials, rune-bonding chambers, and alchemical exhaust vents.  
<br>Citizens of Cindermarch are issued sootmasks at birth.
<br><br><br>
<br>Failure is fuel. If it breaks, improve it.  
<br>Magic is not sacred—it’s machinery in waiting.  
<br>A slow forge cools to ash. Ferrosyn moves fast, even when the sparks burn.
<br><br><br>
<br>Feared by <a data-href="House Keldros" href="houses\arken\house-keldros.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Keldros</a> for their recklessness.  
<br>Respected by <a data-href="House Dravakar" href="houses\arken\house-dravakar.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Dravakar</a> for turning ambition into weapons.  
<br>Distrusted by <a data-href="House Pyrenel" href="houses\arken\house-pyrenel.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Pyrenel</a>, who claim Ferrosyn’s designs echo ancient forbidden sigils.
<br><br><br>
<br>Crafts gear powered by runes, not spellcasting—designed for use by the unGifted.  
<br>Items like combustion gauntlets, reinforced jump-rigs, and siege-saws are common, but dangerous.  
<br>Regularly trades experimental designs with <a data-href="Obelion" href="major-powers\obelion.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Obelion</a>, though tension rises over Ferrosyn’s use of unstable components.
<br><br><br>Ressa Ferrosyn<br>
Runebinder’s Apprentice<br>
Promising young innovator testing a caster-free spellcore. Believed to have bargained with a <a data-href="Shattered Sight" href="major-powers\shattered-sight.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Shattered Sight</a> cultist to obtain Selunian tech.<br>Vel Dranferros<br>
Master Tinker and Safety Overseer<br>
Officially in charge of workshop protocols. Unofficially the most exploded man in the Dominion. Uses a mechanical jaw and steam-powered lungs.]]></description><link>houses\arken\house-ferrosyn.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Houses/Arken/House Ferrosyn.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 20:26:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[House Keldros]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
“Stone remembers flame.”
<br><br><br>House Keldros is the silent cornerstone of the Arken Dominion — not born of fire or magic, but forged through generations of discipline, mastery, and design. They are builders of obsidian cities, architects of lava-fed aqueducts, and custodians of structural balance in a land shaped by eruption.<br>Their legacy is not flashy, but enduring. Where others shout prophecy or raise steel, Keldros lays stone, calculates pressure, and ensures the Dominion does not collapse under its own ambition.<br><br><br>Mael Keldros<br>
Architect-Prince of the Third Hollow<br>
Renowned for designing six cities that have withstood both quakes and riftshock. Never once issued flawed schematics.<br>
<br>Speaks rarely, but his blueprints are considered gospel among Dominion engineers.  
<br>Dreams of “impossible geometries” — designs he claims are whispered from ancient stone.
<br><br><br>A subterranean stronghold carved directly into the obsidian crust below the capital, surrounded by molten rivers and basalt vaults.<br>
<br>Known for its unbreachable vault-doors.  
<br>Houses the Guild of Earthbinding and a deep-locked chamber where failed blueprints are ritually sealed.
<br><br><br>
<br>Greatness is built — not inherited, not gifted.  
<br>Magic is a tool, not a master. It must be wielded with precision.  
<br>The earth holds memory. All design should honor that memory.
<br><br><br>
<br>Respected by <a data-href="House Varnoss" href="houses\arken\house-varnoss.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Varnoss</a> for structural doctrine and siege planning.  
<br>Quietly distrusted by <a data-href="House Dravakar" href="houses\arken\house-dravakar.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Dravakar</a>, who see their restraint as veiled dissent.  
<br>Frequently courted by <a data-href="House Ferrosyn" href="houses\arken\house-ferrosyn.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Ferrosyn</a> for collaboration on lava-forging infrastructure.
<br><br><br>
<br>Uses enchanted tools — not spellcasters — to shape and stabilize architecture.  
<br>Devices like seismic gauges, stabilizing hammers, and lava-channeling rods are standard.  
<br>All tools are regulated by the Guild of Earthbinding and crafted ᚹᚲᚠᛡᚺ ᚲᛈᛚᛇᛠᚲᚠ ᛏᛚ imported ᛃᛏᛟᛇ ᛁᚲᚺᛡᛟᛚᛉᚱᛚᛚᛒ.
<br><br><br>Yrana Keldros<br>
Structural Auditor and Seismic Forecaster<br>
Can detect flaws in stone through vibration alone. ᚲᚷᛠᚨᛚᛚᛠᛚᚾᚹ ᚠᛟᛈ ᚺᚲᚨᛒᛖ ᚲᛡᚨᚱᛋᛖ ᛒᛠ ᛉᛏᚷᛃᛒᛗ ᚠᚦ ᚹᛖᚠᛉᚷ ᛡᛖᛒᛈᛗᛋᛠᛈᛃ<br>Daerin Keldros<br>
Lava-Flow Coordinator<br>
Oversees maintenance of the Dominion’s geothermal channels. Known for his obsession with perfect thermal symmetry and willingness to divert rivers of flame to preserve civic stability.<br>Toval Keldros<br>
Young apprentice and rune-etcher<br>
Born without magic, but developed a tool-enhanced technique for precision rune-carving. Believed to be on the verge of designing a structure that resists ᚹᚹᚺᚠᛚᛗᛖᚷᛋᛋᚱᛋ entirely.]]></description><link>houses\arken\house-keldros.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Houses/Arken/House Keldros.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 20:28:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[House Pyrenel]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
“The truth burns slow.”
<br><br><br>House Pyrenel walks between prophecy and power. They are flame-readers, emberspeakers, and veilwatchers of the Arken Dominion — those who peer into fire and shadow to unearth secrets and shape outcomes. <br>They command no battalions or forges, but revelation itself. Their words can shift campaigns, rewrite succession lines, or burn lies from the minds of traitors.<br><br><br>Elaris Pyrenel, The Ember Oracle<br>
Thin and quiet, always veiled; she has never opened her eyes in public.<br>
<br>Describes distant scenes with perfect clarity — even those she could not have seen.  
<br>Rumored to speak visions not of the future, but of deeper truths waiting beneath reality’s crust. 
<br>One whispered prophecy from her changed three noble successions overnight.
<br><br><br>A sealed, obsidian sanctum built around a slow-burning eternal flame, deep beneath the Dominion’s central caldera.<br>
<br>Its scrolls are heat-tempered, written in flame-reactive ink — only readable by those marked by the Searing Rite.  
<br>Humming with prophecies both fulfilled and still unfolding.  
<br>Guarded by silent monks called the ᛠᛒᛒᚠᚹᚾᛉᚢᛚᛡᛞᛉᚾᛗᛋ
<br><br><br>
<br>Fire is not destruction, but transformation — a trial that reveals.  
<br>Truths must sometimes be veiled, not to deceive, but to avoid collapse.  
<br>Pain is proof that truth has touched you — the unburned are still blind.
<br><br><br>
<br>Trusted by <a data-href="House Dravakar" href="houses\arken\house-dravakar.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Dravakar</a>, who rely on their prophetic guidance.  
<br>Feared by <a data-href="House Varnoss" href="houses\arken\house-varnoss.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Varnoss</a>, who see prophecy as risk without discipline.  
<br>Resented by <a data-href="House Ferrosyn" href="houses\arken\house-ferrosyn.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Ferrosyn</a>, whose innovations are occasionally “predicted” before patents are filed.
<br><br><br>Sylira Pyrenel<br>
Cinder-Warden Archivist<br>
Maintains the sealed chamber of failed prophecies. Once foresaw her own death — and now claims she avoided it.<br>Vaedren Pyrenel<br>
Exiled Seer<br>
A former oracle who refused the Searing Rite and fled to the outer ashlands. Sends back burned letters containing ᛞᛋᚱᛏᛡᛇ ᛒᚾᚱᛡᛒᚲᚢ and ᛉᚱᛞᚠᛠᚺᚷ ᛗᚷᚹᚦᛝᛒ. Some suspect ᛇᚷ ᛈᚱᛟᛒᚷᛗ ᛞᛠ ᛚᛝᚾ ᛞᛃᛒᛃᚾ by the <a data-href="Shattered Sight" href="major-powers\shattered-sight.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Shattered Sight</a> cult.]]></description><link>houses\arken\house-pyrenel.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Houses/Arken/House Pyrenel.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 20:30:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[House Varnoss]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
“Stand where even flame must break.”
<br><br><br>House Varnoss is the steel spine of the <a data-href="Arken Dominion" href="kingdoms\arken-dominion.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Arken Dominion</a>. These are the Dominion’s warlords, tacticians, and builders of ash-bound citadels, commanding the fortresses that line the molten chasms and borderlands. Though fiercely loyal to the Ember Throne, Varnoss is the only house with the military power to challenge it—should they ever turn.<br>Where <a data-href="House Dravakar" href="houses\arken\house-dravakar.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Dravakar</a> rules and others serve, Varnoss endures. Their holdfasts are the first to face outside attack and the last to fall when the world burns.<br><br><br>
<br>Varnoss nobles are towering and disciplined, often marked by ceremonial battle-scars and obsidian-trimmed armor inscribed with kill-counts and unit symbols  
<br>They speak in clipped, precise sentences—even in court—because command must never be misheard  
<br>Children of the house are raised alongside squires and soldiers, learning warcraft before diplomacy  
<br><br><br>
<br>Commanders of the Dominion’s border legions, obsidian wall-garrisons, and mobile war caravans  
<br>Operate the Blackmarch Academies, where both nobles and commoners are trained as elite soldiers and siege tacticians  
<br>Known for breeding and bonding fire-dancing war hounds, hell-boars, and ember-hawks used in border warfare  
<br><br><br>
<br>“Strength in silence, victory in resolve.”  
<br>Varnoss doctrine teaches that honor is shown through action, not oaths. To defend is to rule  
<br>They believe the lava-choked land is sacred because it resists, and any wall that falls must be rebuilt stronger  
<br><br><br>
<br>Unshakably loyal to <a data-href="House Dravakar" href="houses\arken\house-dravakar.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Dravakar</a>—but they watch them all the same  
<br>Tense with mystical houses like <a data-href="House Pyrenel" href="houses\arken\house-pyrenel.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Pyrenel</a>, whom they see as manipulators  
<br>Respected by <a data-href="House Keldros" href="houses\arken\house-keldros.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Keldros</a> for their practical minds and shared love of defensive structure  
<br><br><br>Warlord Caelen Varnoss, Master of the Bastion Line  <br>
<br>A grim woman of fifty winters with ash-gray eyes and a prosthetic arm made of rune-scribed volcanic steel  
<br>Said to have stood alone against a monster born from the lava-rift during the last incursion—and walked away without speaking of it  
<br><br><br>Orek Varnoss<br>
Sergeant-Binder of the Third Blackmarch<br>
Leads a mixed company of warhounds, shieldbearers, and incendiary alchemists. Collects war poetry from every soldier who dies under his command—over 400 pages so far. <br>Aestra Varnoss<br>
Steel Archivist of the Obsidian Vaults<br>
Keeps doctrine and strategic maps for the southern wall. Wears a blindfold, claiming the maps are “best seen without sight.”<br>Taran Varnoss<br>
Disgraced heir of the house<br>
Stripped of rank for “hesitation in command.” Now fights in ceremonial silk with enchanted flame-gloves. ]]></description><link>houses\arken\house-varnoss.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Houses/Arken/House Varnoss.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 20:32:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Cenwyn]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>A city of crumbled secrets, unstable skies, and gnomes chasing echoes from another world.<br><br><br>Cenwyn sits deep inland among craggy hills and half-submerged ruins—remnants of a civilization shattered by Selune’s fall. It is the closest major city to the scars of the collapse, and its landscape bears permanent arcane trauma:<br>
<br>Stones levitate and drift, anchored by forgotten runes  
<br>Clouds spiral endlessly above ruined towers  
<br>Flora glows, sings, or blooms in impossible configurations
<br>Above all, Cenwyn is a city of curious minds, working tirelessly to contain, understand, or repurpose the unstable legacy of Selune.<br><br><br>Gnomes make up the majority of the population, thriving in this world of peril and potential.<br>
<br>Every family maintains a Relic Registry, tracking the artifacts of Selune they've uncovered, lost, or… regretted  
<br>Practical attire includes arcane tool belts, reinforced vests, and radiant crystal accents  
<br>Conversation is rapid, technical, and only slows for metaphor or puzzles
<br>Other groups include:<br>
<br>Rock and deep gnomes, both claiming different historical ties to Cenwyn  
<br>Humans and half-elves, drawn to study the ruins or chase long-lost magic
<br><br><br>Cenwyn is led by the Vault Conclave, a meritocratic council of relic-reclaimers.<br>
<br>Power is earned through discovery, not bloodline  
<br>The current Prime Vaultkeeper is Irix Qindlehop, an eccentric gnome who wears an ancient adaptive mask believed older than the Pactlands themselves  
<br>Influence shifts often — a new breakthrough can change the city’s direction overnight
<br><br><br>
<br>Magic here is volatile — wild surges and ritual backlashes are common  
<br>Despite this, Cenwyn is a hub of magitech and arcane advancement, fueled by relic recovery  
<br>Echo Shards — levitating relic crystals — provide public lighting, wards, or communication links  
<br>Locals refer to Selune as “the dream that cracked open the world”, a phrase used in both reverence and caution
<br><br><br>Cenwyn is one of the most rift-active zones in the continent.<br>
<br>Riftstorms cause seasonal inversion, sky mirages, and soundless thunder  
<br>Dormant portals exist, but activating them often requires unknown conditions  
<br><br><br>
<br>Obelion’s leyline fluctuations are beginning to resonate with rift activity — some fear Selunian mechanisms could reawaken  
<br>A missing relic team returned after encountering warped reflections of themselves — survivors speak of mirrored selves and collapsing realities  
<br>Debate rages: some want to rebuild a gate to Selune’s center, others argue the island should remain untouched
]]></description><link>houses\dravandor\cenwyn.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Houses/Dravandor/Cenwyn.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 20:34:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Estrellan]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>A city of plenty, patience, and deeply rooted traditions.<br><br><br>Nestled in the southern lowlands of the Valewind Pactlands, Estrellan is a beacon of balance and bounty. Golden grain fields stretch beyond the horizon, interspersed with whitewashed stone walls and carefully enchanted irrigation ditches. Life moves slowly here—but deliberately.<br>Estrellan is not a place of innovation, but of wisdom tested by time. Though its halfling residents are often underestimated, their quiet magic and deep-rooted rituals keep half the Pactlands fed and steady.<br><br><br>Halflings are the heart of Estrellan, many tracing their lineage back dozens of generations on the same plot of land.<br>
<br>Homes are earth-rooted, built into rolling hillsides or field boundaries  
<br>Community life revolves around song-archives, seasonal markers, and oral histories  
<br>Though small in stature, halflings wield subtle agricultural magic refined over centuries
<br>Other groups include:<br>
<br>Hill dwarves and gnomes, focused on waterworks, tools, and mills  
<br>Dryads and minor nature spirits, bound in ancestral agreements  
<br>Wandering druids or rangers, offering seasonal aid and protection
<br><br><br>Estrellan is led by the Council of Seeds, composed of elders and farmers selected every seven years by quiet consensus.<br>
<br>Governance is guided by the Cycle Doctrine: “What has worked shall work, until it doesn’t.”  
<br>The current First Chair, Maela Hearthbud, is a blunt but beloved herbalist with an uncanny memory  
<br>Deliberation here is slow by design—rushed decisions are seen as dangerous, especially with magic
<br><br><br>Estrellan’s steady hand sustains the Pactlands through:<br>
<br>Grain, vegetables, and enchanted produce  
<br>Brewing herbs and dreamleaf teas, especially prized in Velmira and Mossmere  
<br>Heirloom seeds with mild enchantments—rot-resistance, frost warmth, or growth-predictive hums
<br>Though rarely flashy, Estrellan’s food supply is irreplaceable, granting it immense political weight without overt force.<br><br><br>
<br>Daily life is interwoven with music, meals, and storytelling—labor is never silent  
<br>Four major festivals mark the turning year:

<br>Blooming Fair (spring)
<br>Harvest Watch (autumn)
<br>Frost Silence (winter)
<br>Rain Rites (early summer)


<br>
“We don’t bend the world. We help it lean where it already wants to go.”
<br><br><br>
<br>Estrellan has refused to expand its farming zones, citing the soil’s need for rest—others call this selfish or outdated  
<br>Rumors of “whispers in the wheat” have spread: ᚠᛝᛡᛠ ᛡᚨᚾᚲᛝ voices ᛖᛇᛠᚠᛁ ᚺᛈ ᛋᛒᚲ fields ᚹᚨ ᛒᛈᛃᛃᛁᛚ ᛡᛉᛇᚺᛋᚲ ᛚᛟᛋᚨᛠᛚ ᚠᚺᛉᛁ ᚦᛋᛋᛠᛒᛏᚾᚢ ᚹᛉ recall ᛋᛉᛚᛚᚦ ᛃᛠᛉᛡᛚ ᛗᚦᚠᛞᚱᚨᚨ  
<br>Though the Shattered Sight cult has made no open moves here, the elders seem increasingly alert and quiet
]]></description><link>houses\dravandor\estrellan.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Houses/Dravandor/Estrellan.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 20:44:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Myrhold]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Capital of the Pactlands, where claws, feathers, fur, and fangs defend the Pact.<br><br><br>Myrhold is a fortified, stone-clad city built atop a high ridge surrounded by deep canyons and fast rivers. It serves as the capital of the <a data-href="Valewind Pactlands" href="kingdoms\valewind-pactlands.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Valewind Pactlands</a> and hosts the rotating High Council, where leaders from enclaves and member cities govern through consensus.<br>Unlike most capitals, Myrhold reflects no single race or culture. Instead, it is a communal stronghold, shaped by the needs and styles of its diverse inhabitants — especially those of animalistic and primal lineages.<br>You'll find:<br>
<br>High roosts for aarakocra
<br>Burrows and heating tunnels engineered by kobolds
<br>Tree-shaded avenues where harengon merchants and lizardfolk guards mingle
<br>Open-air plazas for tabaxi dancers and shifter scouts
<br><br><br>
<br>Shifters – Versatile scouts, spies, and guards  
<br>Tabaxi – Traders, storytellers, performers, and messengers  
<br>Lizardfolk – Practical laborers, hydrological engineers, and stalwart militia  
<br>Kobolds – Tinkerers and civic planners; designed Myrhold’s tunnels and ventilation  
<br>Harengon – Ferry operators, agricultural leaders, and festival organizers  
<br>Aarakocra – Skyward sentinels and council couriers, with aeries along canyon cliffs
<br><br><br>
<br>The High Council convenes every 30 days in the Stone Nest, a massive open-air amphitheater  
<br>Council chairs rotate by consensus between enclaves and cities  
<br>The civil government is managed by a Warden Marshal, elected annually by council vote
<br>Current Warden Marshal:<br>
Skarn Emberplume — an aging aarakocra with a sharp mind and a deep distrust of <a data-href="Obelion" href="major-powers\obelion.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Obelion</a><br>Myrhold values:<br>
<br>Coalition over conquest  
<br>Truth over diplomacy  
<br>Survival over tradition
<br><br><br>While not a commercial hub like <a data-href="Tarnath" href="houses\dravandor\tarnath.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Tarnath</a>, Myrhold thrives by:<br>
<br>Hosting diplomatic negotiations between distant groups  
<br>Maintaining elite defensive contracts and mercenary organizations  
<br>Operating sky-path courier networks and subterranean tunnel transport  
<br>Producing goods via kobold tinkerers and lizardfolk artisans
<br><br><br>Myrhold’s defense systems are legendary:<br>
<br>Multi-tiered walls, built with kobold ingenuity and shifter foresight  
<br>Roost towers used by aarakocra for dive support and long-range alerts  
<br>Hydraulic floodgates capable of redirecting canyon water during sieges  
<br>A diverse militia, where each racial community trains specialized units
<br>The city is called the Roosted Bastion because it doesn’t just resist attack — it actively watches from every height and shadow.<br><br><br>Despite its unity, Myrhold faces pressure:<br>
<br>Obelion’s presence continues to amplify the local leyline — some councilors fear it is reshaping the land itself  
<br>Aarakocra scouts report magical pulses over <a data-href="Cenwyn" href="houses\dravandor\cenwyn.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Cenwyn</a>, possibly signs of rift activity  
<br>A kobold engineer disappeared beneath the old quarry district after unearthing ᛁᛗᛋᛠᛈᚺᚾᛈᛁ ᚢᚲᚠᛠᚹ ᚲᚲ ᚢᛃᛗᛗ ᛗᚾᚹᛗᛡᛁᛁ
]]></description><link>houses\dravandor\myrhold.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Houses/Dravandor/Myrhold.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 20:46:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tarnath]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>A city of firelit sails, masked intent, and smuggled truths.<br><br><br>Tarnath stretches along the sunburnt cliffs of the eastern <a data-href="Valewind Pactlands" href="kingdoms\valewind-pactlands.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Valewind Pactlands</a> coast. Its docks are carved into obsidian-streaked rock and reinforced with black iron. During high tide, waves crash through natural sea-arches beneath the city, earning it the name: “The Singing Cliffs.”<br>Tarnath is a smuggler’s haven, a privateer’s market, and a refuge for the unwanted — especially tieflings. Though it wears the mask of tradition and legitimacy, beneath the surface lie whispered deals, coded contracts, and veiled truths.<br><br><br>Tieflings make up more than half of Tarnath’s population. Many trace their roots to exiles who sought a new beginning far from judgment.<br>
<br>Though not evil, tieflings are viewed with fear and suspicion across most of the world  
<br>Tarnath offers a rare safe harbor for tiefling culture, though even here, old biases still linger  
<br>Cultural markers include brass-inlaid architecture, emberspun cloaks, and fire-dancer traditions
<br>Other notable populations:<br>
<br>Half-orcs – Shipwrights, brawlers, and harbor hands  
<br>Triton – Maintain and navigate deep-sea routes  
<br>Transient merchants – All races, though few settle long-term
<br><br><br>Tarnath is ruled by the Blackscale Accord, a loose council of ship captains, syndicate leaders, and trade barons.<br>
<br>Current Chair: Mariel Skahr, a red-skinned tiefling corsair with a golden eye and a silver tongue  
<br>Publicly supports the <a data-href="Myrhold" href="houses\dravandor\myrhold.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Myrhold</a> High Council, but often pursues independent trade agendas  
<br>Leadership is determined through influence, coin, and clever threat, not election or lineage
<br><br><br>Tarnath is the main port city of the Pactlands and manages:<br>
<br>Spices and rare herbs from <a data-href="Mossmere Basin" href="houses\valewind\mossmere-basin.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Mossmere Basin</a>  
<br>Minerals smuggled across Pactland borders  
<br>Illicit and foreign magical items — often unsanctioned  
<br>Commissioned vessels, including the rare elemental-powered ships
<br>Despite its wealth, Tarnath is distrusted by cities like <a data-href="Estrellan" href="houses\dravandor\estrellan.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Estrellan</a> and <a data-href="Cenwyn" href="houses\dravandor\cenwyn.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Cenwyn</a> — especially for its rumored criminal ties and occult leanings.<br><br><br>
<br>Decorative horns, infernal rings, and ember embroidery are common fashion  
<br>Values freedom, cunning, and results over legacy or pretense  
<br>Night of the Sealed Flame: a solemn candlelit festival honoring ancestral memory  
<br>Local sayings favor wit: “A lie well-spoken is a coin well-earned.”
<br><br><br>
<br>Accused of harboring cultists from the <a data-href="Shattered Sight" href="major-powers\shattered-sight.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Shattered Sight</a>, though no evidence has surfaced  
<br>The docks glow faintly at night, and tides ripple without wind — possible rift activity offshore  
<br>House Delyssar scholars recently arrived under the pretense of trade study — but their true goals are unclear
]]></description><link>houses\dravandor\tarnath.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Houses/Dravandor/Tarnath.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 20:47:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Velmira]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Where illusion cloaks truth, and revolution is rehearsed like theater.<br><br><br>Velmira rests in the highlands west of <a data-href="Myrhold" href="houses\dravandor\myrhold.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Myrhold</a>, nestled among rolling hills of wildflowers, drifting mist, and ethereal twilight. At first glance, it feels more like a dream than a city — its towers twist impossibly, plazas shift with the seasons, and its fog-draped streets conceal both stages and secrets.<br>Once a quiet haven for eladrin and fey-touched wanderers, Velmira has evolved into a cradle of artistry, illusion, and political unrest.<br><br><br>Eladrin form the heart and soul of Velmira, their seasonal moods shaping the very architecture and rhythm of the city.<br>Each district resonates with a seasonal aspect:<br>
<br>Springlight — Passion, invention, youthful optimism  
<br>Summertide — Dueling academies, pride, and vibrant expression  
<br>Autumborne — Philosophy, melancholy, poetic subversion  
<br>Winterveil — Cold resolve, silent rebellion, and covert planning
<br>Other residents include:<br>
<br>Changelings – Welcomed for their fluid nature and kinship with illusion  
<br>Half-elves – Many raised as full citizens of Velmira  
<br>Humans and gnomes – Often drawn by the city’s bardic academies and arcane salons
<br><br><br>Velmira is a Pactlands member in name, but not always in heart.<br>
<br>Governed by the Council of Blooming Masks, whose members are selected every five years through public performance and acclaim, not votes  
<br>True power often lies in salons, underground stages, and revolutionary circles  
<br>Most influential figure: Seran Valquinn, eladrin of the Autumn Court — playwright, cultural icon, and ᛝᛚᚠᚦᚲᛟᚱᚾ ᚠᛗᚷᚠᚱᛟ ᛁᚲ ᛏᛠᛖ ᛋᛖᛇᛒᛡᛠᛞᛠ ᛒᚠᛝᛚᚦᛟᚲᛗᚾᛚᛚᛁᚹᛞ ᛟ ᛃᚠᚢᛠᛚᚱᛞ ᛉᛏᚺᛁᚺᛁᛠ ᚦᛡ ᛟᛃᛖᛗᚢᛠᛠᚹ ᚹᚨᛖ ᛒᚱᚷᚾᛒᛏᚹᚱᛒ
<br><br><br>
<br>Illusion magic is everywhere — from streetlamps and signage to clothing and architecture  
<br>Velmirans speak in double meanings and wear enchanted masks or accessories that shift with emotional state  
<br>Theater is sacred — every major play is a political act, and subversion is applauded more than patriotism  
<br>Some streets only appear at night, or only to those in particular moods or memories
<br><br><br>Velmira exports:<br>
<br>Enchantment and illusion services  
<br>Elite graduates from bardic and arcane academies  
<br>Cultural and theatrical works with magical or ideological weight
<br>Technically illegal activities quietly tolerated:<br>
<br>Illusion-based gambling  
<br>Glamour duels  
<br>Fey-pact ceremonies
<br><br><br>
<br>Radical youth factions demand either independence or resistance to <a data-href="Obelion" href="major-powers\obelion.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Obelion</a>’s influence  
<br>A traveling troupe vanished last month; only their enchanted masks were recovered from Foglake  
<br>Illusory storms have begun sweeping the city unbidden — too complex for casual spellcasters, yet no mage claims credit
]]></description><link>houses\dravandor\velmira.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Houses/Dravandor/Velmira.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 20:50:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[House Elenrath]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
ᛠᛋᛝᛇᚷ ᛡᛁᚲ ᛋᛠᛉᛒᚹᛚᚲ ᛃᛡ ᛡᛚᚠᚦᚨᛗ
<br><br><br>ᛃᚲᚠᛒᚢ ᚷᛉᛉᚦᛁᛉᚱᛉ ᛚᛡᚺ ᛚᛡᛗᚹᛁᛟᚠᚨ ᚲᛝ ᚠᚱᚦ ᛟᚷᛡᛃᛞᚾ ᛠᛃᚾᛠᚱᚺᛗᛖᛖ ᚲ ᛈᚹᚢᛒᛠᚺᚢᛋᛁᛇᛠᛖ ᛉᚦᛋᛠᚦᛏᛟᚱᚾᚦᛞᛁᚺᚠ ᛚᛗᛗ ᚷᚠᚹᛈᛇᛈᚹᛟᚷᛗ ᛞᚱ ᚨᛃᚷ ᛃᚾᛃᚹᛝᚾ ᚠᛡᛠᚱᚨᛡᛇ ᛞᚺᛞᛝ ᛇᛒ ᛖᛁᛇ ᚢᛃᚾᛝᚷᚲᚨ ᛈᛇᛇᛡᚷᛇᚨ ᛞᚦᛁᛡ ᚷᚨᚺᛞᚦᛗᛉ ᛈᚾᛠᚠ ᛟᚷᚲ ᚢᛉᚾᛗᛃ ᛖᚠᛇᛝᛖ ᛞᛒᚺᛡᛃ ᚺᚱᚺᛃᛗᚺ ᛗᚲᚱ ᛟᚾᚠᚦᚺᛡ ᚠᛗᚠᚠᛞᛡ ᚲᚺᛏᛗᛚᛞ ᛝᚷᛚ ᛡᛟᛈᛉᛇᚾ<br>ᚷᛏᛒᛉ ᚺᛉᚠᛟᛉᛒᚱ ᛗᛗᛇ ᚢᚹᛡᚨᚲᛇ ᚦᚲᛟᚲᚱᛟ ᚲᛞ ᛋ ᛝᚱᚦᛚᛋᛖ ᛡᛃᚾᚾᚦᚠᚱᛉᚦ ᚢᚺ ᚦᛏᚨᚺᚠ ᛒᛉᛃᛏᛇᛚᚺᛚ ᚲᚲᚹᛠᛝᛗᚢᛁᚦᛋ ᚲᛈᛖᚱᚠᛉᚱᛗ ᚨᛞᚠᛃᛖᛁᚠ ᛃᛁᚹ ᛃᛁᛏᚨ ᚺᛉᛝᛝᚨ ᚱᛉᛇᛋᛒ ᚢᚺᛠᛁᛈ ᛒᚷ ᛉᚺᛡᛞᚠᛇ ᛖᚺᚾᚺᛖᚹᛗᛈᛈᛗ<br><br><br>ᛃ ᚺᚢᚦᛚᛉ ᛞᚾᛚ ᛁᚲᛇᛗ ᛈᛉ ᛠᛚᛗᚹᚷᛖ ᛖᛉᚢᚹᚦᛏᚹᚠᛏ ᛠᛋᛚᚺᚢᛏᛈᛖᛒᚺᚦᛋ ᛗᚦᛇ ᛈᚹᛞᛒᛁᛁ ᛁᛗᛗᛗᚷᛉ<br>
ᛏ ᛗᛞᛈᛖᛡᛠᛉᛠᛠ ᛈᚦᚨᚱᛠᚾᛞᚠᚹ ᛗᚦᛡᚨᚱᛗᛞ ᛞᚠᛖ ᚹᛋᛇᚠᛡᛖ ᛠᚠᛞᚠᚨᛝᚾᛝ ᛟᛠᛗᚠᚠᚹᛞᛇᚷᛒ ᛉᛟ ᚷᚺᛚᛉᛖᛖᛖᚦᛞ<br>
ᛇ ᚱᛁᚾᛏᚱ ᛚᚲᛁᛁᛡ ᛚᛟᚲᛃᛏ<br><br><br>ᚦ ᚠᛟᛃᚾᛇᛠᚦᛗᚢᚹᛝ ᛖᚾ ᛁᛈᚺ ᚦᚲᛖ ᚺᛈᚠᛏᚦ ᚾ ᛈᛇᛞᚨ ᛁᛝᚠᛈ ᚦᛟᛒ ᚨᛞᚠ ᚷᛁᛈᛉᚾᛖ ᚾᚺᛁᚾᚲᛗᚢᚠ <br>
ᛖ ᛞᚲᚨᚲᚷ ᚾᚢᚹᛃᚱᚨ ᛒᛗᚨ ᛖᚢᛟᛏᛞᛡᚠ ᛝᛟᛚᛖᛃᛝᛈᛏ ᚨᚺᛉᛈ ᛡᛝᚲᛇᛝ ᛉᚾᛗ ᛉᛈᛗᛞᛗᛇ ᛚᛡᚨᛠᛟᚾ ᚠᚱᛋᛝ ᛝᚱᛃᚱᛞ ᛇᛃᚱ ᛉᚷᛟᚠᚾ <br>
ᛁ ᚨᚢᛟ ᛗᛁᚨᚱᛉᚨᚦᛚᚲ ᛁᛞᛃᚾᚨᛉᚷ ᛒᛞᚹ ᚠᚾᛚᚨᚢᚹᚷᛟ ᚺᚾᛚᛉᛡᚹᛖᚨᛞᚾ ᚺᚲᚱᚺᚨ ᛚᛗᚾ ᛃᚨᚢᚲᛝᚲ ᚾᛟ ᛈᚾᛚᚨᚢ ᚠᛋᛖᛚ ᚠᚺᛋᛋᚹᛠᚨᚾᛟ ᛞᚱᚦᛋᛗᛒᚠᛗ]]></description><link>houses\thalor\house-elenrath.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Houses/Thalor/House Elenrath.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 21:27:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[House Ennarion]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
ᚦᛡᚾᚲ ᛋᚨᛒᛒᚹ ᛡᚾᛇᛟ ᛚᚢᚢᛝᛠᚷᛚ ᚦᛈᛉ ᛉᛡᛁᚱᚢᚨ ᚢᛚᚲᚦ ᛏᛚᛡᛗᛃ
<br><br><br>ᛏᛁᛏᛒᛝ ᛖᛚᛈᚢᛚᛠᚢᚹ ᚢᚺᚹᚦᛃᚹᚺᛡ ᚠᚾᛏ ᛚᛇᛋᚦᛗᛈᚺ ᛉᚨᚠᛁᚹ ᛠᚠ ᛞᛉᛇᛝᛟᛁ ᛈᛞᛒᛃᛞᚹᛃᛠᛝ ᚢᛗᛃᚦᛋᛉᛃᛋᛖ ᛇᛇᚠᛡᛇᛖᛞᚷᚾ ᛖᛠᛝ ᛉᚠᚹᛞᛁᛃᚾᛗ ᛗᛝᛃᛠᚱᚦᛗ ᛠᚨᛝᛏ ᚷᛖᛏᚾᛞᛏ ᛝᛏᛏ ᛗᚦᛈᛞᛉᚠᛋ ᚠᛒᛉᛏ ᛡᛋᛏ ᚦᛋᛉᚠᚹ ᛖᛏᚨᚹᛃᛠᛟᚨ ᛈᛃᚦᛞᛞᛋᛈᛃ ᛗᛋᛞ ᚺᚺᛝᛡᚲᚷᛞᛃᛇᚱᛚᛞ ᛇᛋᚲᛠᛝᚷᛉᚦᚷ ᛗᛈᛡᛟᚹ ᛖᛡᛒ ᛞᚢᚦᛃ ᚲᛚᛃᛒᛋ ᚲᚲᛡᚠᛒᛞᛝᚺᛒ ᚦᚲᚢᛡᛟᚺᚺᚠᚢᛇ<br>ᛚᚺᛗᛋᚢ ᛟᚠᛞᛁ ᚢᚷᚦᛚ ᛋᛋᛟ ᛟᚠᚹᛠᛗᛡ ᚺᛏᚠᚦ ᚾᛒᚱᛇ ᚾ ᚺᚲᛗᚷ ᛡᚾᚷᛗᛡᚹᚲ ᚠᛞᚦ ᛝᚲᛈᛡᛖᛃᚹᚺᚹ ᛈᛝᚺᛞᚾ ᛏᛏᛝᚷ ᚾᛃᚾᛃᛒᛉᛗ ᛝᚹᛗᚱ ᛖᛁ ᚾᛚᚹᚦᚹ ᛚᛝᛖᛖ ᚹᚦᚨᛞᛒ ᚷᚦᛏᚠ ᛗᛞᛃᚺᛟᚷᚢᛃᛏᛗᛈᛖᛃᛡᛠ<br><br><br>ᚱ ᛡᛁᛉᛏᛏᚷ ᛟᛠᚢ ᚦᛟᛗᚺᛒ ᛝᛠᛇ ᚺᚷᛋᛈᛞᚠᚹᚨ ᚢᛉᛃᚺ <br>
ᛒ ᚲᛡᛚᚢᛗᚺ ᛝᛡᛞᛁᛖᚷᛋ ᚱᛡᚲᛋᛡᛉᛞᚹᚲ ᛝᛉᛚᛈ ᛋᚾᚾᚦᚢᛚᚲᛉᛝᛝᚷ ᛖ ᛡᚲᚲᚹᚠᚱᛉᚦᚠ ᚷᛖᛖᚾᛚᚨᛋ ᚷᛚᛃᚷᛝᛟᛞᚾᚺ ᛈᛟᛇᛝᚹᛇᚱᚦᛞᛃ <br>
ᚷ ᛞᛈᛇᛚᚨᛗᚨᛟ ᛈᚺᛖᚺᚹᚾᛝᛁ ᛚᚢᛈᚠᛠᛏᛁ ᛚᚱᚷᛇ ᛚᛠᚺᛡᛋᛉᛏ ᛇᛚᚢ ᚠᛈᛖᛖᛝᛖ ᚨᛠᚦᛉ ᛁᛠᛈᛚᛁᚹᛠᛞᛒᚺ ᛋᛖ ᛖᚨᚲᛒᚾᛇᛝ<br><br><br>ᚾ ᛖᛡᚾᚱᚠᛋᛉᚷ ᛉᚱᛏᚷᚱᚹᛉ ᚠᛚᛃ ᛟᚹᛉᚢᛋᚷᛋᛟᛝᚢᛗᛞᛉᛁᛚᛋ ᛠ ᛃᛚᚹᚱᚱᛡ ᛚᚠᚾᛒᛈ ᛡᛋᛝᛋᛡᛇ ᛒᚢᛠ ᚾᛏᚷᛒᚹ ᛉᛃ ᚢᛡᚷᛇᛈ ᛟᛖᛇᛞᛃ<br>
ᚨ ᚱᛗᚢᛖᚷ ᚠᚦᛒ ᛇᚾᚷ ᚷᛉ ᚷᛇᚹᛠᚱᚢᚱ ᛠᛚᛁ ᛠᚢᛒᛋᚠᛇ ᚺᛇᚾᚺᚠᛉᛉᛋᛠ ᚨᛈᛟᛞᚹᚱ ᛚᚢᛏᛇᚦᚠᛞᛉ ᛋᚢ ᛇᚢᚷᛞ ᛝᛞᛟᚨᛞᚢᛈᛞᚢ<br>
ᛖ ᛚᛏᚠᛚ ᛟᚦᛋᚹᛉᛠᚹ ᛈᚹᛠ ᛏᛞᛁᚷᚹᛁ ᚺᚾᛖᛋ ᛠᛃ ᚱᚨᚢᛋᛗᛁᚨᚺᛠ ᛟᛇ ᛖᛖᛋᚱᛇᚲᛠᛒᚹ ᛉ ᛁᛟᛋ ᛖᛇᛋᛟ ᚢᚠᚾᛞᛏᛇᚷ]]></description><link>houses\thalor\house-ennarion.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Houses/Thalor/House Ennarion.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 21:01:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[House Saelthir]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
ᛋᚺᚲᚢ ᛡᚱᚦᛃᛗᚨᛇ ᚺᚺᛡᛏᛗᛏ ᚹᚦᚹᚲᚾᚨ ᛝᛡ ᚠᛚᛉᚲᚦᚦᛠ
<br><br><br>ᛇᛒᚹᚾᚲ ᛚᚦᛝᛒᚲᚾᛡᛝ ᛖᛠᚹᛉᛞᛖᛈᛠᚾ ᛋᛏᛃ ᛖᛡᚺᛇᛇᚺᛉᛗᛒᚾᛇᛇ ᛋᚱᛃ ᛠᚾᛒᛏᛉᚺᚷᚨᛖ ᛉᛗ ᚲᛒᚷ ᛉᚷᚲᛝᚠᛒ ᚲᛁᛟᚱᛞᛈᚹᛚᚠᚱᛉᛈ ᚾᛗᛈ ᛗᚺᛒᛃᚺᚢᛈᛉᚢᛝᚨᚷᛃᛒ ᚢᛗᛚᛉᚹᚨ ᛏᛟ ᚺᚠᚺᚲᛁ ᛚᛒᛉᛋᚺᛞᛚᛏ ᛗᛏᚷᚱᛇᛋᛞᛚᛠ ᛗᚦᛗᚠ ᛈᚨᛞᛃᛈᛏ ᚾᛝᚱᛇᛠ ᛗᚹᛝᚲᛗᛡᛉᛇᛏᛟᚨᛋᚲ ᚱᛚ ᛈᛠᚾ ᛉᚹᛟᛏ ᚲᚹ ᚢᛞᛗᚨᚷ ᚠᛃᛖᛚᛉᛏ ᛠᛖᛟ ᛁᛗᚠᚾ ᚢ ᛈᚢᛈᛞ ᛚᛟ ᛞᚷᛝᚹᚦ ᚾᛠᛏᚨ ᚾᛝᚠ ᛋᚢᚱ ᚹᚷᛖᛏ ᛚᚷᚦᚨᚱ<br>ᚲᚱᛈᛁ ᛃᚲᚺ ᚲᛡᛝ ᛟᚢᚷᚷᛋᛋᛇᛡᛉ ᚱᛞᛡ ᚱᚦᚠᛞᚦᚱᛞᛚ ᛇᛁ ᛡᛁᛏᛋᛋᛚ ᛗᛈᛏᛠᚷᚺ ᚾᛡᚢᛗᚹ<br><br><br>ᚾ ᚦᚲᚱᛠᚱ ᛡᛠᚹᚺᚺᛟ ᛉᛏᛁᛝ ᛟᚱᚱᚹᛟᚲᚦᚺ ᚦᛞᛃᛋᚲᛇᚺ ᚷᚹᛈ ᛃᛝᚲᚢᛝᚾᚢᚱᚾ<br>
ᛉ ᛝᛃᛒᚹ ᚹᛈᚠ ᛈᚨᚢᚲᛠᚱ ᛖᛇ ᛠᚦᛚᚠᛃᛏᛁᛟᛚᚹ ᛒᛝᚾᛁᛈᚲᚲᛖᚠᛠ ᛈᛡ ᛃᚢᛖᚹᛒᛈᚱᚹᚹᛗᛖᛏ ᛃᛒᛈᚲ ᛏᛝ ᚢᚦᛈᚦᚹᚲᚨᚷᚲ ᛠᛖᛖᚷᛡ<br>
ᛗ ᚱᛋᛇᛋᛡᛁᛉᚹᛏ ᛇᛁᛉᛝᛈᛉᚷᛝᛁᛉᚱ ᚲᛖᛟᛞᛠᚷ ᛏᚢᚦᚠᚢᛁ ᛠᚲ ᛝᚲᛋ ᚺᛈᛋᚷᚠ ᛉᛃᚲ ᚨᛒᛃᛃᚨᛠᚠᛉᛋ ᚺᛃᛇᛟᛃ<br><br><br>ᛚ ᚢᚺᚹᛁᛞ ᛋᚷᚱᛡᚾᚱᛠᚠᛟᛝᛝ ᛇᛝᛉ ᚾᚾᚠᛡᚺᚦᛋ ᚺᚨ ᛟᚠᛗᛖᛁᛝᛉᚾᚢᚾ ᛇᚢᛟᚾᚠᛞ ᛟᛞᛃ ᛚᛖᛉᛝᛖ ᚾᛝᛡᚷᛗ<br>
ᛖ ᛠᛈᚷᚢ ᛞᚹᚾᛉᛖᚷᛁ ᛗᛁᛉᛇᚢᚨ ᛠᛏᛖᛝᛟᚾ ᚷᛖᛠᛃ ᚷᛞ ᛃᚢᛝᛖᛃᚦ ᛞᛏᛠᚢᚱᚺ ᛗᚲᚦᚨ ᛃᛃᚠᚱᛡᚨᚨᛖᚲᚺ <br>
ᛝ ᚾᛈᚹᚹᛡᛏᛞ ᛟᛈᛒᛋᚷᛟᚨ ᛖᚠᛈ ᛡᛒᚦᛞ ᛇᛚᚱᛒᚢᚢᛗᛡᛇ ᛒᚷᛁᚲ ᚺᚨᛗᛁᚢ ᚱᚺᚺᚾ ᛋᛇᛠᚺᚦᛗᚾ ᛁ ᛈᛖᛝᚨᛝ ᛠᛡᚹᛝᛖᛡ]]></description><link>houses\thalor\house-saelthir.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Houses/Thalor/House Saelthir.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 21:00:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[House Velasira]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
 ᛋᛡᛖ ᛇᚦ ᛋᛈᛇ ᛈᛚᛋᚦᚹ ᛟ ᛠᛇᛚᚠᚹᛒ ᛋᛃ ᛡᛚᛋᛃᚠ ᛡᛡᛃ ᚨᛒᛋᛗᛖᚺᛝᛈ
<br><br><br>ᛠᛡᚨᚷᚹ ᛠᛉᛚᛝᛝᛁᛡᚨ ᚠᚠ ᚠ ᚷᛟᛋᚦᛗᛞ ᛃᛠᛒᛁᛝ ᛝᛒ ᚲᛒᛃᛋᚢ ᚦᛠᛠᚲᛖᛈᛏ ᛡᚦᛝᚹ ᚹᛚᛇᛚᛟᚨᛏᛒᚷᚲ ᛟᛈᛉ ᚱᚷᛃᛁᛚᛃᛋ ᚦᛁ ᛖᛉᛠᛈᛟ ᛒᛃᚾᚱᛏᚱᛋᚷ ᚨᛇᛋᚨᚹᚢᛗᚱ ᚦᚨᚲ ᛟᚦᚾᚢᛏᛁᛁ ᛝᚺᛗ ᛡᛝᛈᚦᛉ ᛚᛠᛝᛟᛞᚹᚺ ᚨᚺ ᛠᛒᛚ ᛉᚲᛟᚾᛒᚹᚢᛁᛋᚲᚺ ᚾᚱᚺᛠᛒᛗᛞᛒᚺᚷ ᛁᛇᛉᚺᚠ ᚨᛠᛟᚾᛇᛟᛋᚢᛃ ᛉᛃ ᚦᛋᛞᛚᛁᚾ ᛖᛈᛖᚠᚱᚦᚷᛉᛇᛗᚦ ᛟᛟᛝ ᚨᚷᛇᚨᚹ ᛖᚠᛡᛋᚲᛟᚺ ᛉᛋᚦᚾ ᛒᛠᛡᛞ ᛉᚦᚦ ᚷᚠᚹᚾᛇᚢᚦ ᛃᚷᚢᛈᛒᚢ ᛏᛝᚨᛝ ᚹᚾᛟᛈ ᚹᛗᚨ ᛋᛇᛟᛇᛇᛟ ᛗᛖᛃᛒᛠᛁᚾ<br>ᚠᛠᛉᛞ ᛁᚱᛉᛇᚾᛒᚲ ᛒᚨᚱ ᛟᚹᚱᚨᛞ ᛗᚷᛇᛉᚹᚦᛋ ᛠᛝᚺᛇ ᚾᛝᚾᛗᚾ ᛇᚹ ᛈᛖᚹᛗᚺᛝᛉᛁᛡ ᚨᛞᛋᚢ ᛉᛃᚷ ᛋᛒᛁ ᚢᚷᚱᛝᚠᚺᛈ ᚢᚱ ᛝᛏᛒᛏ ᚺᛚᛟᚨᚱᛡᚢᛏᚢ ᚢᛖᛏᛖᛡᚠᚺᛇᛒᛇ ᚲᚢᛏ ᛃᚢᛇᛈᛝᛇ ᛠᛏᛒᛋᛈᛠᛝ<br><br><br>ᚷ ᛞᚠᛃᛉᛡᛠᚲᛟᚹ ᛡᚠ ᚲᛚᚲ ᚱᚠᛝᚷᚲᚾᛏᚲᛠᛚᚺ ᛏᛠᛈᚢᚹᛡᛡᛃᚲᛇ ᛟᚨᛉᛖᚢ ᛉᛡᚨ ᚺᛟᚾᛡᚾ ᛗᚹᚨᛝᛏᛃ <br>
ᛝ ᚷᚾᚲᛠᛞᚹᛝ ᛒᛏ ᛞᚷᚨ ᚢᚾᚢᛖᛡ ᛖᚢ ᛗᛞᛟᛇᚢᛏ ᛖ ᛋᛏᚹ ᚺᛇᚢᚷᚺᚨ ᚾᛁᛇᚱᛡᛇᛃᛋᛒᛠᛖᚦ ᛇᚹᚢᚱᛚᚦ ᛏᛝᚹ ᚲᛡᚱᛒᛏᛖᚺ ᚦᚺᚾᚾᚾᛞᛏᛚ ᛗᛗᛉᛒᛝ <br>
ᛒ ᛇᛇᛒᛋᛃᛒᛝᛗ ᚲᚲᛞᚹᚺᛋ ᚢᛗᛉᚹᛞᛟᚠ ᛠᛇᚢ ᛝᛚᛏᛡᛒᚠ ᛚᛡ ᛝᚨᛒ ᛉᚠᛉᚦᚺᛞᛝ ᛞᚱᛃᚢᚲᚾᚠ ᛟᛗ ᚨᚺᚷ ᛃᛚᚱᛞᛈᛞ ᛋᛇᚷ ᚷᚹᛏᛒᚾᚱ<br><br><br>ᚦᛃᛉᚠ ᛖᚹᛞᛟᚾᛖᛃᚨᛈ ᛖᛋᚾᚢᚹᛏᛝ ᛇᛚᛈ ᚨᛟᚱᛡᛝᛃᛡᛋᛠᛃᛖᚦᛖᛠᚷᚹ ᚾᛟᛃᚢᛖᛝᛉᛚ ᚨᛁᚺᚠᚢ ᛞᛞᛠᛠᛁᛃ ᛟᛚᛈᚷᚢᛠ ᚾᛚᚹᛋ ᛋᚺᛠ ᛚᚠᛗᛠᚾᛋᚲ ᛏᛋᚱᛒᛗ<br>
ᛃᚢᚷᛉᚹ ᚺᚢᛏᛒ ᛞᚦᛝᛖᚹᛉᛟᛏᚺᛏᚢᛇᚦᛏᚺ ᛝᛚᛡᚠᛠᚲᛉᚱ ᛟᛈᚾᛇᚹ ᚲᛒᚦᛡ ᛝᛡᚾᚲ ᛝᛈᛗᛞᛁᚲᛞᛁᛈ ᚷᛁᛡ ᛋᚾᚹᚨᛡᛚᛋᛇ ᚠᚷᛈᚲ <br>
ᛝ ᚲᛃᛒᛋᛈᚲᛉᛋ ᛠᛒᚹᛚᛃᛈᛝ ᛏᛋᛏᛏᛃ ᚺᛟᛁᛠᛁ ᛚᛖ ᚺᛏᛠᛚᛃᚲ ᚨᚷ ᚷᚾᛃᛠᛖᚱᚦ ᚾᛞᚠ ᚢᚨᚦᚹ ᛚᚺᚹ ᛃᛃᛠ ᚺᚹᛁᚠᛁᛉ ᛠᚷᚦᛋ ᚹᛚᚨᛒ ᚷᛏᛡ ᛠᚷᛗᛖᛠ ᚾᛠᛝᛈᛚ]]></description><link>houses\thalor\house-velasira.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Houses/Thalor/House Velasira.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 21:00:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[House Yriveth]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
“The world must never forget us—nor truly find us.”
<br><br><br>House Yriveth serves as the ᛈᛖᚦᛇᛞᚱᛞᛈ ᛋᛠᚷᛡ of <a data-href="Thalor Sylvae" href="kingdoms\thalor-sylvae.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Thalor Sylvae</a>, tasked with managing all elven interactions beyond the forest's veil. They are ᛒᛏᚾᛇᛈᛏᛏᚹᛇᚠᚨᚹᛒ diplomats, ᛁᚲᚺᛋᚨᛉ ᚹᛗᚨ ᛝᚺᛈᛗᚾᚲᛇᚲ ᚷᚾ ᛁᛟᛚᛇᛉᛋᚾᚠ When other kingdoms think they’ve spoken to “the elves,” they’ve spoken to Yriveth.<br>Even among other sacred houses, Yriveth members are regarded with caution. They preserve the queen’s ᚲᛇᛈᛒᚠᛚᛋ ᛠᛖᛒ ᚠᛚ concealment ᚨᚷᛒᚱᚱ ᚱ ᛡᛋᚨ ᚢᛖ ᛇᛠᛟᚲᛈᛖᛏᛋ ᛠᛟᚹᚦ others ᛁᛏᛁᚺᛒᛡᛋ ᛞᛟ truth.<br><br><br>
<br>Serve as emissaries to foreign courts, rarely revealing their true identities  
<br>ᚲᛝᚺᛉᛡ ᛏᚾᛠᚠᛏᛏᛖᚨᛟ ᛈᛝᛃ ᚠᚷᛇᛟᚲᛈᛝᚺᛈᛡᛋᛡᚹ ᚦᚲ ᚾᛚᚲᚹᚠᛒᛗ ᛚᛒᛠ ᛈᛏᛋᛝᛗᛒᛟᚨ ᛚᚹᛏᛋ ᛖᚠᛃᛈᚠᚺᛝ ᛁᛈᚱ ᚲᚨᛡᛋᚺᚨᚲᛟᚠᛗ  
<br>ᛗᛒᚦᚱᚹᛈᛃᛁ ᛡᛡᛃᛟᛇ ᚹᚷᛠᚾᛡᛝᛉ ᚺᛚᛠᛒᛚ ᛒᛞᛏᛇᚺᛖᚱᚲ ᛡᚦᚷ ᛗᛝᛟᚾᛈ ᚱᛞᛇᚢᛒᚺᚹᛠᛒ ᛠᛇ ᛋᛖᚠᛞᛚᛖᚱ ᛒᛖᛗᛗᚦ
<br><br><br>
<br>ᛁᚠᚹᛁᛚ ᛝᛝᚱᛁᛗᚠ ᚨᚷᛝᛖᛏᛉᛠᛠᚷ ᚨᚲᚠᚦᚠ ᚦᛚᛡᛡᛖ ᛚᛃᛚᚦᚺ ᛠᛚᛇᚢᚲᚲᛡᛏ ᛒ ᛃᚨᚲᛁᚲ ᛖᛃᛡᛞᚱᚱ ᛇᛞ ᚦᚾᛋᚱᛃᚲ ᚾᚦᛝᚾ
<br>ᚹᛇᛈᚠᛖᚱᛗᛋ ᚱᛞᚾᚱᛞᛒᛡᛖᚨᚦᛁᛡᛋᛟ ᛞᚦᛏᚠᛝ ᚱᛡᚱᛁ ᚢᚢᛒᚨᛈ ᛈᛉᛁᛝᚨᚹᛠᚱ ᛚᛝᛖᚠᚦᛚᛝ ᚹᚢᛏᛏᛗ ᛝᚨᛖᛝᚹᚺᛝ ᛋᛋᚱᛈᛟᚨᛗ ᚨᛒᚠᛋᚠ ᚲᛠᛋᚠᛋ ᚹᛟ ᛒᛠᚷᛋᛋᛒᛋᛠ ᚢᚨᛠᛇᚾᚱ  
<br>ᚾᚠᚢᛉ ᛡᚦᛋᚺᛠᛇᚲ ᚺᚱᛟᛞᚲᛖᛈᛝᛈᚱᛟᚠ ᛃᚢ ᛖᚷᛇᛏᚨᚢᛒᛈᛃᛖ ᛏᚠᛇ ᛚᛁᛟᛠᚲᚱᚠ ᛟᛋᚷᛝ ᛏᛟᚹᛒᚠᛏᚱᛏᚾ ᛁᚦ ᚺᛚᚢᚠᛠᛗᛗᛏᛗ ᛗᚲᛏᛁ ᛚᛇᚢᚢᚷᚦ
]]></description><link>houses\thalor\house-yriveth.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Houses/Thalor/House Yriveth.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 21:01:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Greenthorn Canopy]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>“We do not rule the tree. We ask. And sometimes, it answers.”<br><br><br>Greenthorn Canopy is a living enclave built into and upon the vast boughs of Yssaviel, a sentient, ancient tree believed to predate recorded history. Suspended above the forest floor, the settlement exists in delicate harmony with the canopy and the elemental leyline that pulses through its roots.<br>It is one of the few places in the world where nature speaks back — not just through druidic interpretation, but literally, when Yssaviel chooses to communicate.<br><br><br>Speaker Thalya<br>
A reclusive firbolg mystic, bonded to Yssaviel through ancient rite.<br>
<br>Serves as both emissary and protector of the tree.  
<br>Speaks rarely, but when she does, her words are treated as the voice of the forest.  
<br>Known to vanish for weeks into the tree’s upper boughs during times of disturbance.  
<br>Said to have been born beneath Yssaviel and raised by its will.
<br><br><br>
<br>Inhabitants live in woven homes of bark, vine, and leaf — shaped with permission, not construction.  
<br>No metal is mined or forged here; tools are made from bone, stone, and enchanted wood.  
<br>Important decisions are made through Listening Circles, where participants commune with Yssaviel via shared dreams or rootbinding rituals.  
<br>Outsiders are welcome, but only after completing a rite of intention under Thalya’s watch.
<br><br><br>The Greenthorn Canopy sits directly above a leyline convergence that hums with pure elemental essence. This energy is channeled through Yssaviel’s roots, branches, and the canopy itself.<br><br><br>Rootwatcher Emril<br>
A blind elf who walks barefoot among the roots, able to interpret tremors in the bark as language.<br>Callen Mossbloom<br>
A half-orc herbalist and musician who trades in rare spores and sings lullabies to Yssaviel’s seedlings.<br><br><br>
<br>Druids of the Outer Circles disagree with Thalya’s isolationist policies, wanting Greenthorn to play a more active role in Pactland defense.  
<br>Some whisper that Yssaviel is sleeping more often, and when it dreams, the air itself changes — ᛏᚢᚨᛁᛁᚹᚦᛃᚲ ᛇᛒᛈᛖᛟᚹᚢᚱᛃᚺᛠᛡ  
<br>A scorched ring recently appeared in the western boughs, repelling all regrowth. No cause has been found.
]]></description><link>houses\valewind\greenthorn-canopy.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Houses/Valewind/Greenthorn Canopy.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 21:03:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mossmere Basin]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>A wide, fertile lowland where the leyline pulses beneath tranquil fields and flowing waters.<br><br><br>Nestled in a broad, mist-shrouded depression in the eastern <a data-href="Valewind Pactlands" href="kingdoms\valewind-pactlands.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Valewind Pactlands</a>, Mossmere Basin is a haven of herbal craft, water-based magic, and elemental communion. The region is lush year-round, its waterways fed by underground aquifers that pulse with leyline resonance, giving rise to flora and fauna found nowhere else.<br>What appears at first glance to be an agrarian settlement is actually one of the most spiritually attuned enclaves in the Pactlands, where the boundaries between the Material Plane and the elemental forces of Water and Life grow thin.<br><br><br>
<br>Canals and terraces dominate the landscape, feeding shimmering rice paddies, medicinal herb beds, and strange floating lily platforms.  
<br>The air is thick with fragrance, from dew-heavy lavender to basil moss and pondblossoms.  
<br>Water elementals, called rillkin, wander freely — most the size of children, some the size of hills.  
<br>Certain trees and reeds hum or sing when touched by wind or rain, resonating with the leyline like living instruments.
<br><br><br>The basin is led by the Circle of the Bloomed Flow, a council of herbalists, spirit-tenders, and druids.<br>Mira Hollowroot<br>
Current speaker of the council. An herbalist-diplomat who has studied at both <a data-href="Greenthorn Canopy" href="houses\valewind\greenthorn-canopy.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Greenthorn Canopy</a> and <a data-href="Obelion" href="major-powers\obelion.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Obelion</a>.<br>
<br>Serves as the bridge between the practical and spiritual aspects of Mossmere.  
<br>Calm, deliberate, and known for carrying live moss on her robes.
<br><br><br>
<br>Herbcraft is more than alchemy — it is a sacred rite, blending plant lore, song, and elemental cooperation.  
<br>Apprentices learn the Three Infusions:  

<br>Sunbrew – tied to warmth and growth  
<br>Dewsteep – tied to clarity and healing  
<br>Rootfold – tied to memory and stillness  


<br>Spirit festivals are held during the Flood Moon, when the wetlands are at their peak and the veil thins.
<br><br><br>Mossmere provides:<br>
<br>The highest quality herbs and spiritual tonics in the region  
<br>Spiritual balancing services to enclaves with unstable magical zones  
<br>Peacekeeping rituals and mediating presence  
<br>A tradition of neutrality, avoiding direct confrontation but subtly shaping outcomes
<br><br><br>While peaceful, Mossmere is not without threat:<br>
<br><a data-href="Obelion" href="major-powers\obelion.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Obelion</a>’s presence has strengthened the leyline, causing some water spirits to become erratic or territorial  
<br>Internal druidic sects debate whether to bind the leyline more tightly or let it flow freely  
<br>Suspected external herb thieves have weakened the balance in certain groves
]]></description><link>houses\valewind\mossmere-basin.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Houses/Valewind/Mossmere Basin.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 21:06:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sablefen]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>A haunted marshland where the oldest pacts linger, whispered to by fog and root.<br><br><br>Sablefen lies in the southeastern marshes of the <a data-href="Valewind Pactlands" href="kingdoms\valewind-pactlands.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Valewind Pactlands</a>, a region of thick fog, whispering reeds, and water that never runs still. It is a place of pacts and promises, where warlocks enter agreements not with devils or fey alone, but with ancient spirits, primordial echoes, and slumbering forces long since abandoned by gods and druids alike.<br>The land is heavy with memory. Every vine and ripple speaks of oaths made, broken, or still binding.<br><br><br>
<br>Light rarely pierces the thick canopy; the air smells of rot, wet bark, and ghost-lilies.  
<br>Fenlanterns — wandering blue lights — guide, mislead, or test travelers.  
<br>The still water reflects more than the sky — sometimes showing secrets or potential futures.  
<br>Voices can carry farther than they should… or not at all.
<br><br><br>Sablefen’s people are mostly warlocks, but they don’t wear the title openly. Here, one doesn’t “cast” a spell — they invoke, entreat, or fulfill.<br>
<br>Locals are quiet, watchful, and tend to speak in layered metaphors.  
<br>They refer to their patrons as “the Bound,” “the Listeners,” or “the Deep Signed.”  
<br>There are no formal schools — patrons choose who they will whisper to.  
<br>Training comes in dreams, rituals, and near-drownings.
<br>Binder Zilma of the Still Veil<br>
A warlock who made her pact with the Root Without Shadow. She can silence a spirit with a glance and is said to keep three promises unfinished — one of which protects the swamp itself.<br><br><br>Sablefen warlocks forge pacts through swamp-bound rituals, dream-walks, and sacred drownings. <br>Common traditions:<br>
<br>The Listening Soak – Sitting submerged in sacred bogs until a pact whispers back  
<br>Swamp Naming – Individuals are renamed when their patron first speaks to them  
<br>The Dimming – A warlock ritually ends their pact, either by outgrowing it… or being consumed
<br><br><br>
<br>Others come to Sablefen when magic fails or spirits turn cruel.  
<br>Their services include curse unraveling, planar negotiations, and retrieving lost knowledge — all for a price.  
<br>The enclave maintains no alliances, but no one dares provoke them either.
<br><br><br>
<br>Since <a data-href="Obelion" href="major-powers\obelion.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Obelion</a> began amplifying the leyline above the Pactlands, new voices have begun speaking to the people — some not native to this plane  
<br>A few warlocks are attempting to bind new types of patrons, creating rifts between tradition and experimentation  
<br>The <a data-href="Shattered Sight" href="major-powers\shattered-sight.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Shattered Sight</a> cult has attempted to recruit from Sablefen twice. They were repelled… but ᚢᛈᚷ ᛃᛁᛈ ᛟᛉᛏᚦᚱ ᚠᚷᛟᛏᚲ ᚺᛋᛏᚨ ᚢᛡᚲᛖᛃᛞᚺᛋᚠ
]]></description><link>houses\valewind\sablefen.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Houses/Valewind/Sablefen.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 21:10:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Stonegrove Veins]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>“The stone remembers. Listen.”<br><br><br>Beneath the surface of the <a data-href="Valewind Pactlands" href="kingdoms\valewind-pactlands.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Valewind Pactlands</a> lies the Stonegrove Veins — a vast underground forest of crystalline growths, bioluminescent moss, and echoing caverns threaded with natural elemental ley pulses. It is a sacred place to earth-touched druids and elemental binders, revered as a living memory of the world’s deep rhythms.<br>Unlike surface settlements, Stonegrove is woven into the landscape. Halls are grown from crystal. Doors are carved into slow-moving shale. The very walls hum with magic — especially when unspoken truths stir below.<br><br><br>There is no singular leader. Stonegrove is guided by the Circle of Shards, a rotating council of druids, geode-seers, and elemental hosts.<br>
<br>The Circle interprets crystal harmonics to guide decisions, believing the land itself speaks through vibration.  
<br>During moments of crisis, an Anchor-Binder is chosen to embody the will of the stone and act as speaker and shield.
<br><br><br>
<br>Memory is sacred. Stones record — through resonance and pressure — all that passes above them.  
<br>Each child receives a Resonant Name, tied to the sound the stone sings at their birth.  
<br>Oral traditions are “sung” into crystals, which replay the knowledge to future listeners when touched.  
<br>Elemental spirits of earth and crystal are revered as ancestors, not just forces.
<br>Visitors are expected to walk barefoot when possible — to offer their full presence to the stone.<br><br><br>
<br>Geode-reading is used to divine the past, not the future. The present is considered unknowable until it echoes.  
<br>Harmonic Trials are rites where initiates must find resonance with a living crystal bloom — not all succeed.  
<br>Forbidden Practice: Resonant Siphoning, ᚢᚷᚱ ᚨᛏᛃ ᚢᚹ ᛇᚷᛇᛡᚢᛟᛒᛝ ᛝᛈᛟᛏᚹ ᚾᛠᚦᚦ ᚦᛚᚢᛋᚹᛏᚺ ᚷᚺᚾᛖᛚᛋᛈ ᛉᛚᛚᚦᛗᛇ ᚱᛠᛡᛈᛖᛝᚠᚨᛚᛠ ᛞᛒ ᛈᛈᛚᛚᛗᚺ
<br><br><br>
<br>Respected by the druids of <a data-href="Greenthorn Canopy" href="houses\valewind\greenthorn-canopy.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Greenthorn Canopy</a> for their elemental balance  
<br>Tolerated by surface nobles, who often find Stonegrove too alien and ritualistic  
<br>Disliked by some <a data-href="Obelion" href="major-powers\obelion.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Obelion</a> scholars, who view their reverence for “dumb rock” as primitive<br>
(a view not voiced aloud within reach of the Circle)
<br><br>Anchor-Binder Kevrin Slateborn<br>
A stone-skinned goliath whose voice can still a tremor. Reluctant to lead, but revered for his calm in collapse.<br>Sister Ruun of the Second Tone<br>
A deep gnome seer who once claimed to hear a song “older than silence.” She has not spoken since.]]></description><link>houses\valewind\stonegrove-veins.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Houses/Valewind/Stonegrove Veins.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 21:13:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[House Branmar]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
“In fire, we shape the will of kings.”
<br><br><br>House Branmar are the forge-lords of <a data-href="Virelia" href="kingdoms\virelia.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Virelia</a>, wielding power not through soldiers or coin, but through the mastery of weapons, armor, siegecraft, and metallurgy. Their forges produce the finest steel in the kingdom, and their techniques are steeped in centuries of tradition — some say even elemental pacts.<br><br><br>Forge-Lord Thandrel Branmar<br>
A gruff, broad-shouldered dwarf with fire-scarred arms and eyes like embers.<br>
<br>Known for walking the foundry floor more than court halls.  
<br>Believes honor is forged in flame, and that politics are best left to those without hammers.
<br><br><br>A fortified mountain citadel built into an active volcanic range.<br>
<br>Home to the Molten Crucible, an enormous magical forge said to burn without fuel.  
<br>Houses one of the kingdom’s only rune-engraving schools, tightly guarded.
<br><br><br>
<br>Believes creation is sacred — a poorly made blade is an insult to the gods.  
<br>Holds a strict guild hierarchy; apprentices must earn every scrap of technique.  
<br>Forges are known to sing with elemental resonance — rumored to be the work of bound fire spirits.
<br><br><br>
<br>Deep allies of <a data-href="House Elstrae" href="houses\virelia\house-elstrae.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Elstrae</a> (shared martial and practical values)  
<br>Neutral with <a data-href="House Vaeron" href="houses\virelia\house-vaeron.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Vaeron</a>, often clashing over prices  
<br>Openly skeptical of <a data-href="House Delyssar" href="houses\virelia\house-delyssar.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Delyssar</a>, considering their “book-bound spells” inferior to flame-wrought enchantments
<br><br>Velra Branmar<br>
Thandrel’s heir; a brilliant forge-mage who believes magic and steel must evolve together, even if it means working with <a data-href="Obelion" href="major-powers\obelion.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Obelion</a>.<br>Master Gralk<br>
Half-dwarf, half-orc smith who claims to have forged with dragonscale in his youth — few believe him.]]></description><link>houses\virelia\house-branmar.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Houses/Virelia/House Branmar.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 21:13:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[House Delyssar]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
“The stars do not shout. They whisper.”
<br><br><br>House Delyssar is composed of arcanists, historians, and keepers of lost knowledge. While not officially part of <a data-href="Obelion" href="major-powers\obelion.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Obelion</a>, they maintain ᚹᚲᛞᛡᚠ ᛁᛡᛒᛚ ᛗᛇᛏᚱ ᚢᛉᛁ ᛚᛚᛃᛗᛟᛗᚱᚾ ᚢᛉᚾᚲᛈᚦ Among the court, they are regarded as eccentric but loyal. Among those who know better, they are dangerous — not because they scheme loudly, but because they don’t need to.<br><br><br>Archlady Serentha Delyssar<br>
Thin, pale, and graceful; always veiled in moonlight enchantments.<br>
<br>Speaks softly, writes constantly, and never forgets a slight.  
<br>Said to have memorized the names of every Obelion mage from the last century.
<br><br><br>An isolated manor overlooking a forested lake under a magically maintained perpetual night sky.<br>
<br>Its library is one of the most complete arcane archives in <a data-href="Virelia" href="kingdoms\virelia.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Virelia</a> — second only to <a data-href="Obelion" href="major-powers\obelion.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Obelion</a>.  
<br>Rumored to house a sealed planar gate in its deepest crypt.
<br><br><br>
<br>Seeks to preserve knowledge, regardless of danger or moral concern.  
<br>Believes magic and intellect must guide the realm, even if from behind the curtain.  
<br>Advocates restraint, but only to protect their secrets.
<br><br><br>
<br>Distrusted by <a data-href="House Branmar" href="houses\virelia\house-branmar.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Branmar</a> (who resent arcane shortcuts to power)  
<br>Monitored by <a data-href="House Thorne" href="houses\virelia\house-thorne.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Thorne</a> (due to past inquisitor disappearances)  
<br>Used strategically by <a data-href="House Vaeron" href="houses\virelia\house-vaeron.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Vaeron</a> (who benefit from magical forecasting)
<br><br>Magister Othenn Delyssar<br>
An old, blind scholar who “reads” tomes by touch and smell; supposedly once touched the <a data-href="Eye of the World" href="major-powers\eye-of-the-world.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Eye of the World</a>’s light and lived.<br>Lyra Delyssar<br>
A teenage prodigy who writes dreams into spellbooks, feared even by senior mages.]]></description><link>houses\virelia\house-delyssar.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Houses/Virelia/House Delyssar.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 21:14:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[House Elstrae]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
“We are the blade the Queen may always draw.”
<br><br><br>House Elstrae is the most respected military noble house in <a data-href="Virelia" href="kingdoms\virelia.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Virelia</a>. Steeped in duty, discipline, and martial tradition, they command both fear and admiration from their peers. They are known not only for their battlefield leadership but also for raising generations of loyal knights, officers, and strategists.<br><br><br>Lord Commander Elric Elstrae<br>
A stoic man in his late 50s, rarely seen without armor.<br>
<br>Once served as general in the east, now semi-retired but still commands respect on the Queen’s War Council.  
<br>Devoted to Queen Araleth VI, and views his house as an extension of her will.
<br><br><br>A massive stone fortress near the Virelian–<a data-href="Dravandor Confederacy" href="kingdoms\dravandor-confederacy.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Dravandor Confederacy</a> border.<br>
<br>Reinforced with siege towers, spell wards, and elite gryphon cavalry barracks.  
<br>Houses one of the most prestigious military academies in the kingdom: the Academy of the Crownshield.
<br><br><br>
<br>Loyalty above ambition — treason is not just a crime, it’s a soul-failure.  
<br>Heavily favors conventional warfare and honor-bound command, occasionally at odds with <a data-href="House Thorne" href="houses\virelia\house-thorne.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Thorne</a> and <a data-href="House Delyssar" href="houses\virelia\house-delyssar.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Delyssar</a>.  
<br>Trains both nobles and commoners — those who graduate may be knighted or fast-tracked into officer corps.
<br><br><br>
<br>Respected by <a data-href="House Branmar" href="houses\virelia\house-branmar.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Branmar</a> (shared martial ethos)  
<br>Tolerated by <a data-href="House Vaeron" href="houses\virelia\house-vaeron.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Vaeron</a> (who consider them inflexible)  
<br>Politely opposed by <a data-href="House Thorne" href="houses\virelia\house-thorne.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Thorne</a> (who finds them easy to predict)
]]></description><link>houses\virelia\house-elstrae.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Houses/Virelia/House Elstrae.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 21:15:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[House Lorentis]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
“From soil to sword, we nourish the realm.”
<br><br><br>House Lorentis controls the vast majority of <a data-href="Virelia" href="kingdoms\virelia.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Virelia</a>’s farmland, grain silos, and food distribution. While they lack flash or political maneuvering, their control over the kingdom’s sustenance gives them unshakable leverage. They are deeply traditional, spiritual, and often the moral compass among nobles.<br><br><br>Duchess Haevra Lorentis<br>
Elderly, warm-hearted, and sharp-witted.<br>
<br>Known to quote saints in council and bake her own bread for temple offerings.  
<br>Famously brokered peace between feuding lords during Queen Araleth VI’s rise to the throne.
<br><br><br>An expansive rural estate surrounded by miles of golden wheat, barley, and vineyards.<br>
<br>Hosts the Chapel of the First Seed, one of the oldest church sites outside <a data-href="Myriath" href="kingdoms\myriath.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Myriath</a>.  
<br>The annual Harvest Festival attracts pilgrims, bards, and commonfolk from across the kingdom.
<br><br><br>
<br>Strong Church affiliation, often seen as the “heart” of Virelia’s faith outside Myriath.  
<br>Upholds values of honesty, hard work, and balance.  
<br>Prioritizes peasant welfare and land conservation.  
<br>Believes the kingdom's strength comes from its well-fed, grounded people.
<br><br><br>
<br>Respected by <a data-href="House Elstrae" href="houses\virelia\house-elstrae.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Elstrae</a> (for their discipline and faith)  
<br>Trusted by <a data-href="House Vaeron" href="houses\virelia\house-vaeron.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Vaeron</a> (as key suppliers in food trade)  
<br>Watched by <a data-href="House Branmar" href="houses\virelia\house-branmar.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Branmar</a> (who worry about grain-for-metal imbalance)
<br><br><br>Sir Kendell Lorentis<br>
A stoic paladin and second son; torn between joining the Church fully or staying to help run the estate.<br>Mira Lorentis<br>
Youngest daughter, secretly gifted with druidic-like magic; considered a “blessing” by some, a “concern” by others.]]></description><link>houses\virelia\house-lorentis.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Houses/Virelia/House Lorentis.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 21:16:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[House Thorne]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
“The rose is lovely… but mind the thorn.”
<br><br><br>House Thorne handles intelligence, internal security, inquisitions, and black operations within <a data-href="Virelia" href="kingdoms\virelia.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Virelia</a>. While they walk the halls of court in noble dress, their real work is done in the shadows — rooting ᛟᚨᛉ ᛡᚹᚦᚲᚲᛉ ᚱᛋppᛇᛝᛝᛖᛉᛁᛠ ᚨᛇᚠᛡlᚦiᚱᛋᛠ ᛉᛋᚹ ᚾᛋᚺᛗᛁᚷᛞᛞᚺᚠᛁ ᛖᛁᛇ ᚷᛈrᛇᛖtᚱᛋᛠᚨ Their loyalty to the crown is unquestionable… but their methods are often unnerving.<br><br><br>Baroness Elsedra Thorne<br>
Regal and composed, with a gaze like a razor’s edge.<br>
<br>Whispers say she can smell lies like perfume.  
<br>Commands the Royal Inquisition and ᛁᛡᛒᛡᛒᛡᛝ ᛠᛋᚾᛃᛝᚱ ᛇᚲᛏᛖᚷᛏᚺᛒᛗᚺ, and sits on the Queen’s High Council… usually silently.
<br><br><br>An austere estate built atop a cliffside ravine shrouded in permanent mist.<br>
<br>Beneath lies the Gloam Archive, a vault of forbidden texts and intelligence records.  
<br>The estate hosts Velspike Hall, where nobles accused of treason are interrogated and judged.
<br><br><br>
<br>Sees truth and loyalty as weapons, to be wielded and sharpened.  
<br>Prioritizes stability over comfort — they will do what is needed, regardless of how it is viewed.  
<br>Believes enemies within are more dangerous than those at the gates.
<br><br><br>
<br>Feared by all, even loyalist houses  
<br>Respected by <a data-href="House Elstrae" href="houses\virelia\house-elstrae.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Elstrae</a> (though uneasily)  
<br>Silently opposed by <a data-href="House Vaeron" href="houses\virelia\house-vaeron.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Vaeron</a>, who believe in soft power over coercion
<br><br><br>Inquisitor Althera Vex<br>
A silver-haired half-elf who speaks rarely, but when she does, her words are binding.<br>Thorn-Lord Darrion<br>
Elsedra’s younger brother; a flamboyant noble who uses his charm and wit to disarm enemies in court, all while feeding them to his sister’s agents.]]></description><link>houses\virelia\house-thorne.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Houses/Virelia/House Thorne.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 21:18:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[House Vaeron]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
“Let others wield swords. We control the weight behind them.”
<br><br><br>House Vaeron is the economic heart of <a data-href="Virelia" href="kingdoms\virelia.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Virelia</a>, controlling major trade routes, coin minting, taxation advisory, and merchant regulation. While they command no legions, their influence reaches every noble household through ledgers, debts, and contracts. In peace or war, House Vaeron profits.<br><br><br>Lady Marenyra Vaeron<br>
A sharp-tongued and brilliant economist in her 40s.<br>
<br>Prefers diplomacy over conflict, but not above orchestrating economic sieges.  
<br>Known for wearing silk robes enchanted to resist wine spills — “a battlefield of its own,” she claims.
<br><br><br>Located in the river-port city of Darsenhal, a vital hub for goods, taxes, and emissary travel.<br>
<br>Home to the Royal Treasury’s reserve vaults.  
<br>Also houses the Guild of Ledgers, where merchant-princes are educated and contracts are magically bound.
<br><br><br>
<br>“Coin is the kingdom’s lifeblood; control the flow, and you control its fate.”  
<br>Views war as a cost-benefit equation. Pushes for diplomacy unless war is profitable.  
<br>Strong believers in meritocracy — several senior advisors are commoners elevated through financial prowess.
<br><br><br>
<br>Trusted by <a data-href="House Lorentis" href="houses\virelia\house-lorentis.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Lorentis</a> (they broker grain trade fairly)  
<br>Tolerated by <a data-href="House Elstrae" href="houses\virelia\house-elstrae.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Elstrae</a> (seen as lacking courage)  
<br>Monitored by <a data-href="House Thorne" href="houses\virelia\house-thorne.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Thorne</a> (for suspected foreign dealings)
<br><br><br>Silven Vaeron<br>
Lady Marenyra’s estranged cousin; runs a rogue trading company believed to operate out of the <a data-href="Valewind Pactlands" href="kingdoms\valewind-pactlands.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Valewind Pactlands</a>.<br>Thresik Bale<br>
Vaeron’s orcish finance minister, known for ruthless tax enforcement and a love of exotic teas.]]></description><link>houses\virelia\house-vaeron.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Houses/Virelia/House Vaeron.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 21:18:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Arken Dominion]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>The Arken Dominion is a theocratic empire fueled by divine zealotry and volcanic might. Centuries ago, it led the purge that nearly wiped dragons from the world. For this crime, it was cursed by a dying red dragon whose flame turned their capital into a volcano—one they now harness for power.<br>
<br>Type: Religious Empire / Theocracy  
<br>Ruler: Emperor Kavalh, Flame-Ordained  
<br>Capital: Varkhaz-Thul  
<br>Magic: Only divine and state-sanctioned arcane magic  
<br>Military: Zealot legions and firebound warpriests  
<br>Alignment: Lawful Neutral (with fanatic overtones)
<br><br><br>The Dominion believes its destiny is to shape the world through divine fire and purification. Faith and loyalty to the Flame Creed are absolute. Technology and craftsmanship are advanced, powered by lavaforges and sacred flame rituals.<br>
<br>Common Language: Drakhan (shared with older dwarven dialects)
<br>Religion: The Flame Creed (a fusion of divine law and elemental fire worship)
<br>View on Magic: Only ordained warpriests and flamebound mages may practice
<br><br><br>Each noble house commands a vital pillar of the Dominion’s volcanic empire—whether through industry, flame-wrought magic, or martial might. While most swear loyalty to the Ember Throne, the true depth of their ambition is often hidden beneath the ash.<br><br>
<br><a data-href="House Dravakar" href="houses\arken\house-dravakar.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Dravakar</a> – Flamebound royals and heirs to the dying wyrm’s curse.
<br><a data-href="House Varnoss" href="houses\arken\house-varnoss.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Varnoss</a> – Ash-wall generals and obsidian-clad bastion keepers.
<br><a data-href="House Pyrenel" href="houses\arken\house-pyrenel.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Pyrenel</a> – Secretive seers who read truth from flickering flame.
<br><a data-href="House Keldros" href="houses\arken\house-keldros.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Keldros</a> – Elemental architects of obsidian cities and silent ruin.
<br><a data-href="House Ferrosyn" href="houses\arken\house-ferrosyn.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Ferrosyn</a> – The Lords of Iron Will
<br><br><br>A city built into the heart of a volcanic canyon, where lava flows through artificial channels like blood in stone veins. Its forge-halls produce enchanted weapons, plate, and siege machinery.<br>
<br>Features: Blackstone sanctuaries, molten moats, obsidian bridges
<br>Notable Institutions:

<br>Temple of the Flamewrought Path
<br>Crucible Archive (artifice and relic study)
<br>Ashborn Forges (military production)


<br><br><br>
<br>Standing Army: The Dominion Legions (organized into flamewrought cohorts)
<br>Specialty Units:

<br>Ash Disciples – battle-chaplains infused with divine fire
<br>Infernal Engines – lava-fueled siege golems
<br>Ember Cloaks – elite assassins sworn to the Purging Light


<br>Adventurers: Viewed as undisciplined. Rarely employed directly.
<br><br><br>
<br><a data-href="Virelia" href="kingdoms\virelia.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Virelia</a> – Maintains peace, but tensions simmer beneath diplomacy
<br><a data-href="Myriath" href="kingdoms\myriath.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Myriath</a> – Publicly respectful; privately resentful of the Barrier's rejection
<br><a data-href="Obelion" href="major-powers\obelion.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Obelion</a> – Distrusted; arcane interference seen as heretical
<br><a data-href="Thalor Sylvae" href="kingdoms\thalor-sylvae.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Thalor Sylvae</a> – No formal contact
<br><a data-href="Valewind Pactlands" href="kingdoms\valewind-pactlands.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Valewind Pactlands</a> – Considered primitive and nonthreatening
<br><a data-href="Dravandor Confederacy" href="kingdoms\dravandor-confederacy.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Dravandor Confederacy</a> – Labeled as anarchic and godless
<br><br><br>
<br>Core Belief: Only through sacred flame can impurity be burned away
<br>Saints of Fire: Revered martyrs who perished in flame
<br>Dragons: Considered divine enemies, their extinction a holy mission
<br>The Curse
The death-curse of the final red dragon scorched the land, but the Dominion twisted it into a symbol of strength and holy transformation.
]]></description><link>kingdoms\arken-dominion.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Kingdoms/Arken Dominion.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 21:20:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dravandor Confederacy]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>The Dravandor Confederacy is a union of five independent city-states that formed a defensive alliance against the growing power of <a data-href="Virelia" href="kingdoms\virelia.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Virelia</a>. Though united in name, each city maintains its own identity, laws, and leadership. Internal tensions and ideological differences prevent full cohesion, but the shared threat of invasion keeps them aligned.<br>
<br>Type: Confederacy of free cities
<br>Structure: Semi-independent city-states with a rotating High Council
<br>Capital (rotating): Currently Myrhold
<br>Military: Diverse and decentralized; relies on regional militias and contracted adventurers
<br>Magic: Lightly regulated; varies by city
<br>Alignment: True Neutral to Chaotic Good
<br><br><br><br>
<br>Known for its strategic location and strong walls
<br>Hosts the rotating High Council
<br><br>
<br>A coastal trade hub with a vast black market
<br>Major port for smuggling and privateers  
<br><br>
<br>Home to bards, artists, and illusionists
<br>Politically rebellious, culturally vibrant
<br><br>
<br>Deep inland city surrounded by ruins
<br>Recently uncovered relics from Selune
<br>Rift Activity  
Cenwyn is a known site of unstable rift energy and strange magical weather. ᛚᚨᚱ ᚹᛒlt ᚱᚲᚺᛈᛉ ᚱᛈ ᛞᚢᛏ ᚹᛋᛈᚾᚦᚺᛡᛉᛗᚹᛒ ᚲᚷᛃᛠᛋᛃᛗ ᚦᛝᛃ infiltrated ᛋᛝᚺ ᛡᚷᛈᛟᛖᛉᚹᛗᛒᚠ
<br><br>
<br>Agricultural powerhouse
<br>Conservative in governance, slow to act militarily
<br><br><br>
<br>Each city is ruled by a local council or elected archon
<br>High Council meets twice per season; rotates by city
<br>Laws vary per city but Confederacy-wide rules protect member sovereignty and mutual defense
<br><br><br>
<br>Magic is freely practiced in most cities, though Cenwyn now places restrictions near rift zones
<br>The Confederacy has close ties with the <a data-href="Adventurer’s Guild" href="major-powers\adventurer’s-guild.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Adventurer’s Guild</a>
<br>Local mages from <a data-href="Obelion" href="major-powers\obelion.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Obelion</a> often visit for research or diplomacy
<br><br><br>
<br>No standing army
<br>Each city maintains its own militia
<br>Hires adventurers and mercenaries for major campaigns
<br>War with <a data-href="Virelia" href="kingdoms\virelia.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Virelia</a> is costly; most fighting takes place near Myrhold and Tarnath
<br><br><br>
<br><a data-href="Virelia" href="kingdoms\virelia.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Virelia</a> – At war
<br><a data-href="Myriath" href="kingdoms\myriath.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Myriath</a> – Spiritual ally, but politically distant
<br><a data-href="Obelion" href="major-powers\obelion.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Obelion</a> – Valued for magic and healing aid
<br><a data-href="Valewind Pactlands" href="kingdoms\valewind-pactlands.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Valewind Pactlands</a> – Trade partner; seen as unreliable in war
]]></description><link>kingdoms\dravandor-confederacy.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Kingdoms/Dravandor Confederacy.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 21:22:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Myriath]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Myriath is a shining city of marble domes, golden spires, and holy silence—widely considered the spiritual heart of the continent. Though referred to as a “kingdom,” it is a single autonomous city-state led by the Church that venerates the martyr-saint Vivi. Myriath maintains neutrality in all wars, offering sanctuary, healing, and divine guidance to those in need.<br>
<br>Type: True Neutral Theocracy  
<br>Ruler: The Council of Halos (symbolically led by Saint Vivi)  
<br>Alignment: True Neutral (Public); subtle Good leanings  
<br>Military: No formal army, but elite paladins and clerics patrol the mountains  
<br>Protected by: The Perfect Barrier
<br><br><br>Saint Vivi cast the Perfect Barrier 100 years ago before dying, leaving behind a ward that detects alignment and repels all who harbor evil. It is located at the base of the northern mountain range separating the civilized world from the realm of monsters.<br><br><br>
<br>The Council of High Clerics interprets Vivi’s teachings and oversees doctrine.
<br>The Sanctum of Radiant Peace is the seat of divine power and home to the barrier's origin.
<br>Regional Priories answer to Myriath’s spiritual authority but govern their local churches.
<br><br><br>
<br>Central Faith: The Radiant Path (based on the teachings of Saint Vivi)
<br>Tenets:

<br>Do no evil, knowingly or otherwise
<br>Serve the light in word, action, and memory
<br>Defend the innocent, but do not seek war


<br>Healing is sacred and reserved for those of pure intent
<br>Alignment is considered part of the soul; those of evil alignment cannot enter Myriath at all
<br><br><br>
<br>No formal army
<br>Paladins, clerics, and divine wardens guard the city
<br>Divine ᛃᛚᚲᛟᚠᚨᚲᚹᛚᛉ known as ᛃᛗᚨᛖᚷᚾᛟᛈ ᛏᚹᛈᛏᛉᛋᚷᛞᛋᛉᛋ patrol the inner sanctum
<br><br><br>
<br><a data-href="Virelia" href="kingdoms\virelia.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Virelia</a> – Respected and often aided with healing, but politically distanced
<br><a data-href="Dravandor Confederacy" href="kingdoms\dravandor-confederacy.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Dravandor Confederacy</a> – Peaceful relations; provides sanctuary to injured
<br><a data-href="Arken Dominion" href="kingdoms\arken-dominion.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Arken Dominion</a> – Cold. Officially neutral, but distrust simmers beneath
<br><a data-href="Obelion" href="major-powers\obelion.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Obelion</a> – Academic allies. The Tower wishes to replicate the barrier
<br><a data-href="Thalor Sylvae" href="kingdoms\thalor-sylvae.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Thalor Sylvae</a> – Spiritually aligned but rarely in contact
<br><a data-href="Valewind Pactlands" href="kingdoms\valewind-pactlands.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Valewind Pactlands</a> – Mutual respect; healers often assist in natural disasters
<br><br><br>A shimmering white and gold garment worn by Saint Vivi’s incorporeal form. It glows gently at all times and amplifies divine magic, especially alignment-based effects. It also houses the final spark of Vivi’s mortal soul, binding her spirit to the material plane.<br>
<br>Serves as both relic and lock to the sanctum’s divine reservoir
<br><br><br>A relic of divine mercy and mortal sacrifice, this staff stands rooted in the sanctum of <a data-href="Myriath" href="kingdoms\myriath.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Myriath</a>, radiating the pulse of the Perfect Barrier.]]></description><link>kingdoms\myriath.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Kingdoms/Myriath.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 21:24:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Thalor Sylvae]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Thalor Sylvae is the ancient forest kingdom of the elves. Once active in continental affairs, the elves have largely withdrawn into their ancestral groves, leaving the world to unfold without them. Their kingdom is cloaked in dense, enchanted woodlands—resistant to divination and nearly impossible to enter without permission.<br>
<br>Type: Dreaming Monarchy  
<br>Ruler: Queen Liraethe Velyndor 
<br>Capital: Thandoril, the Glade of Stars  
<br>Military: Elite rangers and forest guardians  
<br>Alignment: True Neutral
<br><br><br>ᛠᚦᛡᛠᚷ ᚦᛈ ᚹᛇᛒᛁᛒᚲ ᚷᚢᛉᚺᛡᚷ ᛡᛁᚢᛁ ᛈᛋ ᛒᚺᚹᛟᛞᛗᚲ ᚺᚨᚠᚨ ᛃᚨᚺᛉᛇ ᛈᛈᚦᛇᛟᚹᚹᚠᛏᛃᛝᛡᛗ ᛖᛠᚠᚦᚠ ᛁᛋᛈ ᚹᛝᚷᛒᛖ ᚠᛚᛡᛚ ᚲᛗᛁᛗ ᚾᛇᛟᛇᛡᛠᛉᛖᛝ ᛃᚹᚲᚹᚢᚷᛟᚢᛖ ᛋᛞᛝᛁᚢᛗᚨᚨ ᛈᚹᛒᚢᛡᛟ ᚾᛃᚠ ᚨᚱᛈ ᛞᛒᛝᛉᚢᚢᚾᛡ ᛁᚢᛗᚢᚱᚨᛈ ᛏᛁᛈᚢᚹ ᚲᛏᛃ ᛒᚠᚠᛇᛃᛏᛚ ᚾᛖ ᛉᛝᛏᛡᛝᚦ ᛝᚦᚠᛚᛏᛏ ᛁᛟᛒᚺᛈᛠ ᚨᛏᛗ ᛟᛉᛏᚾᛚ ᚺᚾᛗ ᛁᛉᛖ ᚾᚱᚺᛋᛠᛞᛞᛚᚢᚢ ᛡᛋᛡᛡᚲᚷ ᛠᚱᛞᛋᚺᛈᚦ ᚺ ᛒᛞᚱᚾᛈᚺ ᚹᚷᛝᚱᛡᛏᛟᚷᛖ<br>ᛏ ᚱᚷᛟᛗᛇᚷᚢᛇᚾ ᚾᛝᚨᛁᚲᚷ ᚹᚲᛒᛗ ᛗᛠᛚᛃᛏᛉᛒᚱ ᛋᚠᛁᚷᚷᚾ <br>
ᚢ ᚱᚱᛝᚹᛇᛏᚨᛡᛒ ᛈᛏᛟᚾᚲ ᚾᛉ ᛋᚦᚢ ᚷᛚᚠᚢᚨᛁᚦᛇᚦᛖᛚ ᚺᚺᛠᛁ ᛟᚨᛏᛃᛝᚹᚱᛃ ᚺᚨᛞ ᚺᚷᚠᛡᛇᛠᛗᛈᛉ ᚾᛏᛞᚦᛏᛇ <br>
ᛚ ᚨᛒᚢᛗ ᛡᚲ ᚹᛠᚺᛇᚱᛒ ᛋᛖᚲᛒᛝᛞᛋᚱᛁ ᛗᛈᚨᚦᚾᚷᛃ ᛝᛃᛉᚦᚲᛁᛗ ᛚᛒᛇᛡᛟ ᚱᛁᛒᛁᛃᚢ ᚱᚠᚹᛋᚾᛋᛞ ᚹᛏᛏ ᛁᚲᛒᚱᚢᚾᛇ<br><br><br>Queen Liraethe Velyndor ᛖᚠᚾ ᚦᛒᚨ ᛏᛃᛒᛁᛈᛗᛚᛒ ᛁᚢ ᚲᛖᛠᛝ ᚢ ᚲᛟᛈᛃᚱᛝᚹᛞ ᛞᛠᚲ ᛋᛝᛚ ᛗᚲᛟᛋᛗᚷᛗᛒᚠ ᛡᛡᚷᛉᚹᛠᚲᛁᛖ ᛝᚲᛁᚢ ᛈᛋᛖ ᛗᛝᛋ ᛈᛝ ᛡᛋᚢᛈᚨ ᚲᚹᚱᚱᛗᛁᛒᛋᛏᚾ ᚠᛇᛟ ᛝᚠᛟᛁᛖᛗ ᛒᛟ ᛈᚹᚲᛗᚺᛏᚨᚾᚷ ᛏᛞᚷᛋᛡᛝᛞ ᛒᚷᛋ ᚾᚹᚢ ᛝᛇᚨᛃᛋ ᚠᛉᛁᛈᛏᛒᛒᛏᛋᚷᚾᛗᛋᚢ ᚠᚦ ᚹᛇᛉᚠᚺ ᛚᛚᚠᛏ ᛒᛞᚱᚨᛚ ᚦᛡᛝᚢᛏ ᛡᛖ ᚦᛗᚨᛡ ᛉᚠᚾᚹᛒᛞᚷᛏᚠᚱ ᛉᛚ ᛞᛋᚱᚷᚨᛗ<br>ᛃ ᛉᛗᚷ ᛝᛇᛁᛚᛏᛇᚱᚠᚲᛡ ᚦᚷᛃ ᛒᚾ ᛖᛁᛃᚱᛒᛒᛚᚲᛁᛗ ᚨᛁᛁᛝᛖ ᚷᛇᚺᛗᛖ ᛡᛁ ᚲᚢᛞ ᛡᚲᛟᛗᚢᚾᚷᚨ ᛝᛇᚨᚦᛝᚷᚢ<br>
ᚷ ᛖᛗᚺ ᚾᚾᛋᚺᚨᛒ ᚷᛝᛃᛒᚺᚷᛇᛖᛈᚠ ᛖᚱᛚ ᛝᛟᚠᛠᛖᚷ ᛉᛞᛈ ᛟᛒᚱᛒᛟᛃ ᚦᛖᚲ ᚱᚢᛉᚾᚹᚦᛃ ᛠᚠ ᚠᛖᚺ ᛝᛁᚷᚾᛗᛗ<br>
 ᛚᛞᚠᛇᚦ ᚺᚾᚢ ᛉᛠᛋᛗ ᚲᚾᛏᚹ ᚺᚾᛟ ᛃᛃᛚᛝ ᚾᛡᚠᛉ ᚾᚷᚷ ᚢᚾᛗᚹ ᛃᚱᚠᛃᛃᚺᚹ ᚺᚹᛉᛠᚠᚷᚠᚦᛚᛏᚷᛒᚾᛏᛚ ᚺᛞᛃ ᚲᛞᚷ ᚨᚺᛗᛁᚠ ᛡᛋᚾᛏᛃᚺ ᚹᛝᚺᛋ ᛞᛚᛈᚲᛇᛞ ᚲᛃᛃᛚᛠᚹ
<br><br><br>These houses are not political powers, but devoted stewards, bound by oath and ancestry to the queen. They serve specific functions to preserve the culture, magic, and vision of Thalor Sylvae.<br><br>
<br><a data-href="House Velasira" href="houses\thalor\house-velasira.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Velasira</a> – ᛝᛗᛉ ᚹᛇᛖᛈᛖᚺᛏᛟ ᛋᛟᛃᚷᚲᚠ ᚲ ᛝᛚᚾᛁᚲᛇᛞ ᚦᚹ ᛒᛁᛡᛉᛁ ᛃᛟᚱᚦᚦᛝᚺᛈᚱᚲ ᚺᛇᚱᛏ ᛉᛃᛝ ᛏᛃᚢ ᛒᚾᛟᛠᚲᛖᚷᛋᛈ ᛖᛗᛗᚨᚺᚦᚷᚨ
<br><a data-href="House Ennarion" href="houses\thalor\house-ennarion.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Ennarion</a> – ᛁᛁᛝ ᛇᚲᛉᛚᛃᚲᛏᛇᛃᛚᚢ ᚲᚢᛃᚢᛞᛠ ᛁᛝᛏᛗᛠᛞᛝᛖᚷ ᛇᛋᛟ ᛁᚲᛉᛉᛟᛠᛏᛚᛚᛞᛒᛏ ᚹᛡᚾᚢᛟᚾᛒ ᛋᛟ ᚲᛝᛠ ᛈᛒᚺᛁᛚᛝᚱ
<br><a data-href="House Saelthir" href="houses\thalor\house-saelthir.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Saelthir</a> – ᛡᛟᚹ ᛋᛇᛋᛉᚨᛞᛗᚲᛟᛈᚷᛠ ᚱᛟᛒᛈᛡᛏᛈᛈᚱᛖ ᚺᚷᚲᛞᛗ ᚷᚦᛖ ᛝᚱᛁᚾᛖᛝᚱᚨᛞᛟᚺ ᛁᚠ ᚹᛖᛇ ᛋᚲᚲᚺᚦᛁᛗ ᚹᚲᛈᛉᚱᚾᚷ
<br><a data-href="House Yriveth" href="houses\thalor\house-yriveth.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Yriveth</a> – The Hollow Veil; elusive diplomats and maintainers of elven illusion.
<br><a data-href="House Elenrath" href="houses\thalor\house-elenrath.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Elenrath</a> – ᛏᛗᛈ ᚺᛁᛠᛟᛖᚺᛉᛏᛃᚱᛒᛟ ᛃᚢᛟᚱᚲᛏᛁ ᛠᚺᚾᛈᛡᚺᚢᛝ ᚾᛚᛠ ᛁᚺᛡᚦᚠᚺᚷᛇᛡ ᛃᛖᚹᚢᛡᛇᛟ ᚢᛁᛖᛃᚾᚨᛟ ᛖᚲ ᚦᛟᛠ ᛁᛏᛠᛗᚲᛠᛠᛃ ᛈᚾᚠᛠᛝ
<br><br><br>Located deep in the Dreaming Glade, Thandoril is a luminous forest city woven from light, leaves, and music. The buildings sing in the wind, and the trees whisper when visitors approach.<br>
<br>Notable Locations:<br>
ᛉ ᚹᛠᚲ ᛗᚨᛖᛖᛞᚹᚾᛖ ᚺᛡᛝᚦᛈᚦ ᛖᛖᚺᚷᚢᛗᛃᚷ ᛠᛒᛖᚾᛡᛞᚠ ᛏᛖᚦᛇᚷᛇ<br>
ᛏ ᚺᚠᛡᚲ ᚹᚾ ᛋᚾᚷᛟᚷᛡᛝ ᛝᛃᚲᚠᛃᛡᛗ ᛈᛋᛁᛃᛏ ᛠᚾ ᛒᛟᚢᛟᛋ ᛞᚷᚷᛉᛉᛟ<br>
ᚲ ᛗᛇᚱᛠᚠᚱᛠᚷᚲᚦ ᛇᛖᛈᛟᛠᚲᛠᚢ ᛋᛇᛖᚾᚷᚾ ᚢᚺᛃᚱᛝᚠᛈᛇᚨ ᚲᛖᚲ ᛈᚲᚢᛡᚨᛃᛞᛟᛏᛒᛚ
<br><br><br>ᛇ ᚹᛈᚠ ᛖᛒᚱᚦᚷᚺᛋᛇᛗᛉᛈᚱ ᛏ ᚱᛒᚱᛝᚺ ᛖᛋᚱᛏᛒᚾᛉ ᛉᛇᚾ ᛟᛡᛃᛝᛏᛋᚨᛝᛝᛟᚲᛃ<br>
ᛟ ᚦᛁᚠ ᛈᛁᚱᚨᛡᚹᚾᚷᚹ ᛒ ᛚᚨᛗᛃᚱᚺᚱᚾᛁᛚᛞ ᚠᚺᚺᛉᛇᚠᚹᛇ ᚠᚾᚠᛝ ᛒᛞᛝᚦᚢᛈᛒ ᛠᛝᛝᛠᛒᛈᛚᚦᚹ<br>
ᚠ ᚠᛋᚠ ᛖᛝᚲᚨᛇᚠᛟᚹ ᚲᛠᛖᛟᛃᚾ ᚲ ᚢᛇᚱᚠᛈᛟᛝᛒᚹᛠᚹᛡᛚᚠ ᛇᛝᛠᚹᛃᛏᛇᚾᚹᚷ ᛈᚱ ᚾᚱᛈ ᛡᛚᛝᛡᚾ<br>
ᚦ ᚨᛝᛞᛈᛝ ᛞᚨᛚ ᛉᚱᚨᛠᛁᚺ ᚹᚺᛚ ᛖᚨᛇᚲᚱᚾᚨᚱ ᛞᛞᛃᛋᚱᛚᛖ ᛈᚠᚾᛚᛉᚹ ᛏᚺᛚᚲᛝ ᛗᚨᛇᚠᛁᚠᚲ<br><br><br>
<br><a data-href="Valewind Pactlands" href="kingdoms\valewind-pactlands.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Valewind Pactlands</a> – Close allies through old druidic ties
<br><a data-href="Virelia" href="kingdoms\virelia.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Virelia</a> – Viewed as meddlesome and short-sighted
<br><a data-href="Dravandor Confederacy" href="kingdoms\dravandor-confederacy.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Dravandor Confederacy</a> – No formal contact
<br><a data-href="Myriath" href="kingdoms\myriath.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Myriath</a> – Neutral respect; some elven scholars revere Saint Vivi
<br><a data-href="Obelion" href="major-powers\obelion.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Obelion</a> – Warily observed but not opposed
<br><a data-href="Arken Dominion" href="kingdoms\arken-dominion.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Arken Dominion</a> – Deeply distrusted, especially for dragon-slaying history
]]></description><link>kingdoms\thalor-sylvae.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Kingdoms/Thalor Sylvae.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 21:29:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Valewind Pactlands]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>The Valewind Pactlands are a loose federation of druidic enclaves, nature-bound towns, and leyline sanctuaries. Bound by ancient pacts, not crowns, the Pactlands serve as neutral stewards of balance and renewal. They hold no standing army, but their land is fiercely protected by awakened beasts, forest spirits, and gifted rangers.<br>
<br>Type: Druidic Federation / Council Rule  
<br>Governance: Council of Speakers (one per major enclave)  
<br>Capital: No formal capital; Speaker's Meeting held at various sacred groves  
<br>Military: None; defended by magical wards, beasts, and druids  
<br>Alignment: Neutral Good
<br><br><br>The Pactlanders live close to nature, often with semi-permanent homes that blend into trees, cliffs, or living hills. Different enclaves follow their own traditions but share a reverence for the balance between life and death, growth and decay.<br>
<br>Languages: Common, Sylvan  
<br>Religion: Nature spirits, ancestral roots, elemental forces  
<br>View on Magic:

<br>Druidic magic is sacred
<br>Arcane magic is accepted if tied to natural leyline currents
<br>Artificial magic (e.g., constructs, necromancy) is frowned upon


<br><br><br>The land itself pulses with magical power. Several leylines intersect in Valewind, feeding the forests and influencing druidic rites.<br>
<br>Obelion’s floating island currently resides above Valewind.
<br>Its presence strengthens the central leyline—an unexpected phenomenon.
<br><br><br>
<br><a data-href="Greenthorn Canopy" href="houses\valewind\greenthorn-canopy.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Greenthorn Canopy</a> – Built atop an ancient sentient tree, led by Speaker Thalya (a dryad-kin)
<br><a data-href="Stonegrove Veins" href="houses\valewind\stonegrove-veins.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Stonegrove Veins</a> – Underground crystal forest; home to geode-based elemental rites
<br><a data-href="Mossmere Basin" href="houses\valewind\mossmere-basin.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Mossmere Basin</a> – Wide agricultural basin where herbcraft and elemental water spirits flourish
<br><a data-href="Sablefen" href="houses\valewind\sablefen.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Sablefen</a> – A shadowed swamp where older pacts linger; often avoided
<br><br><br>
<br><a data-href="Obelion" href="major-powers\obelion.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Obelion</a> – Officially tolerated; informally monitored
<br><a data-href="Myriath" href="kingdoms\myriath.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Myriath</a> – Respected, but many druids distrust divine interference
<br><a data-href="Virelia" href="kingdoms\virelia.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Virelia</a> – Dismissed as rigid and blind to nature
<br><a data-href="Dravandor Confederacy" href="kingdoms\dravandor-confederacy.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Dravandor Confederacy</a> – Occasional allies via shared trade and adventuring routes
<br><a data-href="Thalor Sylvae" href="kingdoms\thalor-sylvae.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Thalor Sylvae</a> – Old ties with elven druids remain strong
<br><br><br>
<br>No standing army
<br>Defense relies on:

<br>Ancient magical pacts
<br>Druid circles
<br>Tamed beasts and forest guardians
<br>Occasionally aligned adventurers from the <a data-href="Adventurer’s Guild" href="major-powers\adventurer’s-guild.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Adventurer’s Guild</a>


]]></description><link>kingdoms\valewind-pactlands.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Kingdoms/Valewind Pactlands.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 21:30:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Virelia]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Virelia is a powerful and centralized monarchy known for its disciplined military, strong bureaucracy, and strict regulation of magic. It is currently at war with the <a data-href="Dravandor Confederacy" href="kingdoms\dravandor-confederacy.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Dravandor Confederacy</a>, seeking to assert dominance over what it sees as rebellious city-states.<br>
<br>Type: Centralized Monarchy  
<br>Ruler: Queen Araleth VI  
<br>Capital: Caer Thalor  
<br>Primary Conflict: War with the <a data-href="Dravandor Confederacy" href="kingdoms\dravandor-confederacy.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Dravandor Confederacy</a>  
<br>Magic: Heavily regulated and licensed by the crown  
<br>Military: Professional, rigidly trained, loyal to the throne  
<br>Alignment: Lawful Neutral to Lawful Good (public-facing)
<br><br><br>Virelia’s society values order, tradition, and loyalty. The Queen is seen not only as a political figure but a symbol of national identity. Education and military service are encouraged among the nobility. Art and architecture reflect martial beauty and royal propaganda.<br>
<br>Common Language: Virelian (a refined dialect of Common)
<br>Common Religions: Church of the Radiant Path (follows <a data-href="Myriath" href="kingdoms\myriath.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Myriath</a>'s Saint Vivi)
<br>View on Magic: Regulated like a military resource
<br><br><br>Most noble houses are loyal to the crown. Nobles are expected to maintain regional order, collect taxes, and fund soldiers during wartime.<br><br>
<br><a data-href="House Elstrae" href="houses\virelia\house-elstrae.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Elstrae</a> – Military tacticians; loyal and proud.
<br><a data-href="House Vaeron" href="houses\virelia\house-vaeron.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Vaeron</a> – Wealthy trade magnates and economists.
<br><a data-href="House Lorentis" href="houses\virelia\house-lorentis.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Lorentis</a> – Agricultural lords and grain providers.
<br><a data-href="House Branmar" href="houses\virelia\house-branmar.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Branmar</a> – Forge-lords with deep ties to master smiths.
<br><a data-href="House Thorne" href="houses\virelia\house-thorne.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Thorne</a> – Oversees covert operations, spies, and inquisitors.
<br><a data-href="House Delyssar" href="houses\virelia\house-delyssar.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Delyssar</a> – Scholars and minor mages who keep to themselves.
<br><br><br>A grand stone city built on a high ridge with deep catacombs and tiered walls. It houses the royal palace, central barracks, the Academy of Arms, and the Royal Seal Tower where magical licenses are issued.<br>
<br>Features: Clockwork courtyards, ceremonial guards, strict curfews during wartime
<br>Notable Institutions: Virelian College of Governance, Royal War Council
<br><br><br>
<br>Standing Army: The Royal Legion (divided into four field armies)
<br>Specialty Units:

<br>Sky Lancers (gryphon riders)
<br>Arcane Sentinels (licensed battlemages)
<br>Stoneguard (heavy infantry)


<br>Draft Policy: Voluntary enlistment with noble-sponsored incentives
<br>Adventurers: Cannot openly join the army but may be hired as mercenaries under royal charter
<br><br><br>
<br><a data-href="Dravandor Confederacy" href="kingdoms\dravandor-confederacy.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Dravandor Confederacy</a> – Active conflict; seen as rebellious
<br><a data-href="Myriath" href="kingdoms\myriath.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Myriath</a> – Revered for Saint Vivi; respected
<br><a data-href="Obelion" href="major-powers\obelion.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Obelion</a> – Watched carefully; officially tolerated
<br><a data-href="Valewind Pactlands" href="kingdoms\valewind-pactlands.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Valewind Pactlands</a> – Viewed as passive and backward
<br><a data-href="Thalor Sylvae" href="kingdoms\thalor-sylvae.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Thalor Sylvae</a> – Distrusted due to isolationism
<br><a data-href="Arken Dominion" href="kingdoms\arken-dominion.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Arken Dominion</a> – Neutral, but tensions exist due to history of magical extremism
]]></description><link>kingdoms\virelia.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Kingdoms/Virelia.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 21:30:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Adventurer’s Guild]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>The Adventurer’s Guild is a transnational organization that offers contracts, certifications, and logistical support to those rare individuals gifted with the ability to level up. The Guild maintains neutrality in all conflicts and does not serve any crown or kingdom.<br>Its main headquarters is not part of any nation—it exists as an independent town, fortified and self-sustaining, where adventurers train, rest, and report. Only those bearing a recognized Guild emblem may enter the central tower.<br>
<br>Type: Independent Free Town  
<br>Leadership: The Grandmaster of Quests and the Circle of Guildmasters  
<br>Alignment: True Neutral  
<br>Motto: “For coin, cause, or challenge—walk the path.”
<br><br><br>The Guild operates in tiers, both for adventurer ranking and organizational authority. Every regional guild reports to the central HQ.<br><br>(from lowest to highest):<br>
<br>Porcelain  
<br>Copper  
<br>Bronze  
<br>Iron  
<br>Silver  
<br>Gold  
<br>Platinum  
<br>Mithril  
<br>Orichalcum  
<br>Adamantite  
<br>
Note: Mithril and higher ranks can only be achieved through extraordinary deeds and a formal recommendation by a Guildmaster or higher.
<br><br><br>The HQ town—known as Steelmark—is built on neutral land between major kingdoms. It is fortified like a citadel, but functions more like a merchant-adventurer republic.<br>
<br>Includes:

<br>Training grounds  
<br>Contract halls  
<br>Arcane registry  
<br>Alchemical shops  
<br>Small arena for mock trials and public duels  
<br>Airship pad (restricted access)  


<br><br><br>
<br>The Guild does not take sides in wars.
<br>Adventurers who act in war are seen as mercenaries, not official agents.
<br>Guild contracts are public record. Every quest must be registered.
<br>Failure to report actions may result in rank loss or expulsion.
<br><br><br>
<br>Grandmaster Reign Evershade – Oversees the central HQ and final rank promotions
<br>Mistress Vallan of Maps – Coordinates geographic contracts and lost ruins
<br>Eldren Flintmark – In charge of the bounty ledger and monster classifications
<br>Lyss of the 12th Bell – Handles inter-kingdom communication and arbitration
<br>Korrak the Bold – Head of physical training, veteran Ironblood
<br>Orichalcum Circle
The highest-ranked adventurers—Orichalcum and Adamantite—form a secretive inner order. Only the Grandmaster knows all of their names.
<br><br><br>
<br><a data-href="Virelia" href="kingdoms\virelia.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Virelia</a> – Respected but distanced
<br><a data-href="Dravandor Confederacy" href="kingdoms\dravandor-confederacy.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Dravandor Confederacy</a> – Maintains open trade with Guild-run towns
<br><a data-href="Myriath" href="kingdoms\myriath.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Myriath</a> – Openly welcomed; healing provided in emergencies
<br><a data-href="Obelion" href="major-powers\obelion.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Obelion</a> – Collaborative research agreements for magical adventurers
<br><a data-href="Arken Dominion" href="kingdoms\arken-dominion.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Arken Dominion</a> – Hostile territory; Guild branches operate covertly
<br><a data-href="Valewind Pactlands" href="kingdoms\valewind-pactlands.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Valewind Pactlands</a> – Neutral but cautious
<br><a data-href="Thalor Sylvae" href="kingdoms\thalor-sylvae.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Thalor Sylvae</a> – No formal contact
]]></description><link>major-powers\adventurer’s-guild.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Major Powers/Adventurer’s Guild.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 21:32:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Eye of the World]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
“Where the Eye gazes, truth breaks.”<br>
— Fragment from a salvaged Selunean hymn
<br><br><br>Once the heart of Selune, the Eye of the World was a towering arcane structure seated on the circular island at the center of the crescent-shaped Selune. Believed to predate even the Kingdom of Selune itself, the tower was more than a seat of power—it was a trial, a beacon, and a containment vessel for the darkness that stirred beneath the island.<br>The Eye collapsed centuries ago when the island of Selune fell into chaos and was lost to the world. Its fall ripped open the veil between realms, letting in monsters, corrupted magic, and artifacts from beyond the known world.<br><br><br>Only in the final years before the fall was the Eye’s true nature rediscovered:<br>
<br>
🔺 A Trial of Succession:<br>
The tower was not simply a royal symbol—it was a test. Deep within its halls lay a series of arcane and moral trials, meant to judge and prepare a candidate to become the Vessel, a ruler tasked with absorbing and containing the darkness below Selune.

<br>
🌀 An Arcane Beacon:<br>
The tower channeled leyline energy through Selune. Scholars believe it maintained magical equilibrium between the material plane and something outside it.

<br>
🔒 A Seal:<br>
The Throne of Sealing, located at the tower's summit, was both a crown and a cage. Each Vessel who sat upon it bound themselves to the darkness, delaying its escape through self-sacrifice and strength of will.

<br><br><br>The final Vessel, a once-noble king, was corrupted by the very force he was meant to contain.<br>
Rather than dying to protect Selune, he turned on his people, shattered the tower’s inner wards, and helped bring about the island’s destruction.<br>The collapse:<br>
<br>Tore open rifts between planes
<br>Released monsters and magic not seen in the world before
<br>Caused Selune’s total isolation, leaving it unreachable by magic or sea
<br><br><br>In the final years before Selune’s fall, the truth about the Trial of the Eye became known. One last group of adventurers, renowned across the continent, attempted to ascend the tower and seal the darkness anew:<br>
<br>Rune, a warforged mage whose very design echoed the lost machines of Balance  
<br>Valira, a tiefling warlock scorned by society, but gifted in weaving truths from the Void  
<br>Athena, a human paladin whose faith had once caused monsters to flee at her presence  
<br>And a fourth, never named in any surviving record—some say by choice, others by necessity
<br>They failed. Whether they fell during the trials, were betrayed by the throne, or simply could not reach the summit in time is unknown. But their attempt marks the last known act of resistance before the tower was consumed by darkness.<br><br><br><br>
<br>Founded by a mage who came into contact with the broken throne long after the collapse.  
<br>This survivor claimed the Eye whispered truths that no mind was meant to hold.  
<br>A rift-born monster confirmed the visions before its death, giving rise to a fanatic belief that the Eye was divine.
<br>
“We are not meant to seal the Eye. We are meant to be seen by it.”
<br><br><br>
<br>A few fragments of tower, etched with runes that reshape when not looked at, have appeared in the hands of collectors, heretics, and the Delyssar.  
<br>One cultist’s blade, said to be forged from throne-shard metal, has the ability to "remember" each person it kills—growing heavier with each soul.
<br><br><br>
<br>The throne at the tower’s peak still exists, broken but not powerless.
<br>Some say the Eye was never meant to contain evil, but to draw it in like a lure for something greater.
<br>Certain storm-wracked nights bring echoes of Selune’s final cry to distant shores.
<br>Obelion wants access to surviving throne fragments—but Myriath forbids it.
]]></description><link>major-powers\eye-of-the-world.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Major Powers/Eye of the World.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 21:34:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Obelion]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Obelion—known as the One True Tower—is the last unified mage tower in the world. Built on a floating island suspended by ancient magic, it is both sanctuary and laboratory for the most gifted arcanists. Obelion maintains neutrality in global conflicts, but its eyes are everywhere.<br>
<br>Type: Arcane Institution (Floating Island)  
<br>Leadership: The Circle of Five (rotating archmage council)  
<br>Goal: Advance magical knowledge and replicate the Perfect Barrier  
<br>Mobility: The island can move slowly over months  
<br>Alignment: Lawful Neutral
<br><br><br>
<br>The floating island is anchored magically to the skies
<br>Movement is slow and deliberate, requiring months to change regions
<br>Currently resides above the <a data-href="Valewind Pactlands" href="kingdoms\valewind-pactlands.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Valewind Pactlands</a>, where magic is tolerated and leylines are strong
<br>Island Features

<br>Skyward Hall – central tower and lecture spire  
<br>Leyforge – where leylines are bent into power sources  
<br>Vault of Mirrors – a library of reflection magic and prophecy  
<br>Astral Garden – a floating crystal dome for planar study  
<br>Windstep Docks – suspended platforms where airships or guests arrive

<br><br><br>Obelion radiates strong arcane energy that empowers spells cast nearby. The floating island’s position affects leylines in the region below.<br>Leyline Effects
The Tower’s presence is strengthening the central leyline of the Pactlands. Druids are divided:

<br>Some fear destabilization if Obelion leaves  
<br>Others warn that this concentration of magic might awaken forgotten powers

<br><br><br>
<br>Replicating the <a data-href="Perfect Barrier" href="Perfect Barrier" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Perfect Barrier</a> of Saint Vivi is a top priority
<br>Study of rift energy, planar bleed, and remnants of Selune is ongoing
<br>Accepts magically gifted individuals from all nations—status or origin does not matter
<br><br><br>Obelion avoids war and refuses military contracts, maintaining total neutrality.<br>
<br><a data-href="Virelia" href="kingdoms\virelia.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Virelia</a> – Cordial but distant  
<br><a data-href="Dravandor Confederacy" href="kingdoms\dravandor-confederacy.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Dravandor Confederacy</a> – Occasionally aids with magical study  
<br><a data-href="Myriath" href="kingdoms\myriath.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Myriath</a> – Admired; seeks knowledge of the Barrier  
<br><a data-href="Arken Dominion" href="kingdoms\arken-dominion.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Arken Dominion</a> – Deeply distrusted due to anti-arcane beliefs  
<br><a data-href="Thalor Sylvae" href="kingdoms\thalor-sylvae.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Thalor Sylvae</a> – Holds mutual respect for ancient magics  
<br><a data-href="Valewind Pactlands" href="kingdoms\valewind-pactlands.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Valewind Pactlands</a> – Current host region; fragile balance with druids
<br><br><br>
<br>Archmages rotate by specialty and era. Current seats:

<br>Archmage Veridan – Transmutation and leyline stabilization
<br>High Seer Elora Vell – Divination and prophecy
<br>Master Ghallor Tane – Planar studies and void defense
<br>Scribe-Lord Kael of Chains – Forbidden magics and sealcraft
<br>Mistress Aivenna of Glass – Illusions and diplomatic outreach


<br><br><br>
<br>A leyline surge below Obelion threatens a Pactland settlement—Obelion wants a team to investigate.
<br>A mage has gone missing after researching the nature of the Barrier—last seen near <a data-href="Cenwyn" href="houses\dravandor\cenwyn.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Cenwyn</a> in the Confederacy.
<br>A rogue faction within Obelion seeks to descend the island permanently—help or stop them?
<br>]]></description><link>major-powers\obelion.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Major Powers/Obelion.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 12:22:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Shattered Sight]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>A cult born from broken truths and divine madness.<br><br><br>The cult was formed by a mage who journeyed to the ruins of Selune long after its collapse — centuries after it had vanished from maps and memory. This mage, whose name has been lost or erased, reached the shattered summit of the <a data-href="Eye of the World" href="major-powers\eye-of-the-world.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Eye of the World</a> and touched the remains of the broken throne. What they saw changed them.<br>They returned not with riches or relics, but with visions, half-mad poetry, and unsettling truths. Many dismissed them. Some listened. A few followed.<br>Everything changed when a rift-born monster, already revered by a fringe group, spoke its final words to the mage:<br>
“The Eye remembers you.”
<br>It then died laughing.<br>This moment marked the cult’s divine confirmation — the mage had not gone mad. The Eye was still watching.<br><br><br>
<br>
The Eye ᛇᛠᚹ ᛚᚺᚨ ᛡᛋᚲᛠᚱ ᚷᛋ ᚹᛇᛁᚱᚦᚺᛗᛠᚷ<br>
ᛁᛖᛠ ᚲᚾᚺᛈᚹᚱᛚᛒ ᛡᚲ ᚲᛁᚢᛗᚹᚺ ᛉᚠᚢ ᛗᚺᚷ ᛚ ᛝᚨᛚᚺᛚᛞᛚ ᛋ ᛝᛋ ᛒᚾᛃ ᛠ ᛁᛚᚢᛞᛡᛋᛋᛗᛁᛋᚱᚨᚠᛖᚹ ᛉᛏᛈ ᛚᛚᚲᛚᛞ ᛟᚹᚷᚹᛇᛃᚱᛒᛝ ᚢᛠᚱ ᛝᛟᚺᚷᚷᛋᛠ ᛝᛇ ᚹᚱᚨᛞᛠᚱᚹ ᛒᚾᛚ ᛠᚹᛝᛗ ᚠᛝ ᚢᛚᛋᛠᛠᛉᛁ ᛞᚾᚢᚨᛒᛞᚦᚺᚦᛈᛈᚷᛈᛗ

<br>
The throne is ᛗ ᛒᛈᚱᛝᚾᛒᚲᛞ ᛃᚷᛠ ᛁ ᛉᚱᛝᛝᛚ<br>
ᚢᛋᚲ ᚨᛟᛒᛏᛁᚷᛃ ᛝᛖᛁᚦᛒᛞᛞ ᛟᛗᛉᛞ ᛃᚢᛞᛃᛋ ᛠᛝ ᛈᛗᛉᛡᛖᛗᚠᛈ ᛡᛉᛖ ᚠᛇᛚᛡᛈᛏᚢᚲᚱ ᚱᚾᚦ ᛠᛁᚦᛝ ᛃᛟᛉᚨᛗᛗᚱᛞ ᛖᛠᚺᛁ ᛞᛞᛠᛃᚷ ᛃᚱᛒᚷ ᛒᛉ ᛏᚨᛠᛠᛟᚠᛝᛗᚨ ᚨᛈᛠ ᛝᛋᛃᚦᛠᛖᛡ ᛇᛞᚦ ᚢᚷᛗ ᛒᚲᛞᛋ ᚦᚲᚢᛗᚾᛞᚠ ᛖᛉ ᛝᚨ ᚱᚾᛠ

<br>
The world is broken ᚱ ᛟᛠᛝᛇ ᚺᛈᛁ ᚷᛠᛡᛞᚲᛗᛝ<br>
ᚠᚢᛋᚲᛚᛉ ᛈᛚ ᛋᚠᛏᛚᛡᚺᛖ ᚦᛈᛚᛝᚠ ᛚᚱᛝᛋᚷ ᛃᚲᚷᛝᛒᚠ ᚷᚺᛡᚷᚠᛖᛝ ᛋᚦᚲ ᛋᛒᛃᚨᚾ ᚾᛈᛈᚠ ᚺᛒᛈᛚᛃ ᛖᚺ ᚺᛁᛝᚹᚷᛡᚦ ᛉᛒᛒ ᚺᛠᚨ ᛏᛋᛈᚱ ᚾᚺᛡᛡᚠ ᛚᛃᚦᛃ ᛞᚺᛝᛠᚾᛈᛚ

<br>
One day, a ᚾᛝᛃᛞᛁᛈ ᛏᛖᚷᚷ ᚢᚾᛉᛒᛒᛇᚠ<br>
ᛈ ᚹᚷᛒᛟᛞᚺ ᚺᛒᛗᛟ ᚲᚲᛟᛏ ᚱᚷᚷ ᛒᛝᛟᛠ ᛟᛉᛠ ᚦᛇᚨᛗᛡᛋ ᛁᛉᚷᚺᛝᛝ ᚹ ᛡᛁᚢ ᛒᚺ ᚢᛠᛗᛈ ᛗᛚᚲ ᛗᚲᚨᛉᛡᛈᚠᛁᛝ ᛞᛝᚦ ᛃᚷ ᛈᚺᛚᚹᚺᛇ ᛗᛖᛋᚱ ᛏᛏ ᚺᛏᛏ ᚱᛖᚦᛗ ᛡᛃᛇᚨ ᛝᚹᚠᛋᛞᛖᛉ ᚺᚦᛝ ᛡᚢᚺᚹᛏᛏᚱ ᛚᛝᛁᚲᛚᚨᛉᚢᛟᚱᚢᛞ ᛈᛈᚱᛖ ᛚᛚᚲ ᚲᚺᛞ ᛟᛋᛠᚢᛉ ᚱᚨᚾ ᛇᚾᛖᛠ ᛉᚦᛖᛈᚨᛖᛉᛞ

<br><br><br>The Shattered Sight is not a centralized religion, but a scattered network of seers, radicals, and hidden cells. Each group is called a Shard, and no two operate the same way. Some hide in cities, whispering in dreams; others carve glyphs into cave walls and wait for visions.<br>Each Shard follows a ᛁᛚᛈᛡᛒᛁᛃᛃᛝᛠᚺᛡᛃᛁᛠᛉᚱ ᛃ ᛁᛏᛗᛃᚹᛞᛡ ᚦᚢᚦ ᚷᛒᚨ ᛠᛈᚹ ᛟ direct ᛝᚢᛝᚾᛏᛋᛇᚲᚨ ᛒᛞᛇᛡ ᛏ fragment ᚷᛋ ᛡᛒᚹ ᛇᛒᚠᛉ ᛇ ᛚᚦᛒᚦᛞᚢ ᚦᚦᛃᚱᛝᚠ ᛞᛃ ᚺ rift-born ᛟᚨᛃᚾᚺᛒ<br>Notable Shards:<br>
<br>The Whispering Fold — ᚹᚠᛋᚱᛏᛠᛞᛁ ᛚᚾ ᚠᚷᛚᛖᚲᚷᚾᛈᚺᚺᛠᚲ circles, ᛟᛝᚺᛈᛞᛒᛈᛁᛁᛚᛉ ᛗᛗᚲᛟᛖᚠ ᚲᛋᛚᚺ ᛁᛒᚨᚠᛞᛉᛉᛚ ᚠᚷᚨ ᚲᛒᚱᛠᛞᛚᚷᛋᛏ
<br>The Molt-Sighted — Swampᛝᛇᚲᚷᚾᛏᛏᛗᚲ ᛝᚹᛃ ᛖᚠᛈᛠᚠᛠᛖ ᛈᛞᛗᛃᛏᛡᛉᚦᚠᚨᚲᛠᚢᛝ ᛠᛟᚦᛖᚱᛚᛈ ᚹᚨᛃᚢᚾᚱᚾᚺᚲ ᛟᛠᛇᛃᛗᚷᚹ ᛖᚠᚨ ᚱᛉᛠᚦ
<br>The Crownless Path — ᚨᚢᛇᚠᛁᚲᛚ ᛠᚠ ᛞᛞᛈ ᛏᛉᛈᛈ ᛠ fourth ᛚᛗᚠᛁᚱᛖᚱᛖᛗᛒᛝ ᛉᛠᛈ ᚲᚨᛠᚹᛗᛇᛡ ᚠᛇᚷ ᛈᚢᚨᚺᛈᛚ ᛞᛈᚷᛟ ᛡᛟᚾᛖᛋᛁᛞ ᚾᛝᛡᚺ ᛟᚺᚦᚾᚲᛏ ᛟᛟᛉᛁᛋ ᛖ ᛇᚦᛇ ᚷᛝ ᛈᛝᛡ ᚱᚨᛒᚱ
<br><br><br>
<br>Members wear ᛋᛋᛉᚾᛏᚾᛃᚱᚦᛖ ᛈᚠᚾᛇᛝᚹᛏᛠ or ᛉᛃᛠᛚᚹᛏᚨᚷ ᛡᛖᛝᛃᛏᛉᚢ ᛁᚨᚾᛡᚱᛉᛉᛗᚠᛉ to “focus” their inner vision.  
<br>Instead of prayer, they perform ᛉᛋᚢᚨᚲᛚᛞᛒᚢᚺᛗᛞᛒᚲᛚ ᛡᛗᛠᚹᛠᛠᛏᚠᛟ, often using drugs, relics, or leyline storms to ᛚᛚᚨᚢᚷᚾ ᚠᛞᛈᚨᛗᛇᛋ ᛝᛖᛃᛞᛒᚲᛃ  
<br>Acolytes carve spiral glyphs into stone, bone, or flesh — never with the same pattern twice.  
<br>Names are often discarded and replaced with Eye-given titles:<br>
ᛋᚷᛋᚠᚺᛉ ᚺᚦᛚᛈᛒᛁᛒᛝ ᛞᛞᛚᚦᚹᛋ ᛏᛞᛟᚺᚹᛃᛗᚨᚨ ᚢᚲᛉᛝᛡᛡ ᛖᛃᛗᛝᛇᛇᚨ ᛡᚦᛋᚾᚦᛖᚢ ᚢᛞᚢᛟ
<br><br><br>
<br>The cult is largely unknown or dismissed, but <a data-href="House Thorne" href="houses\virelia\house-thorne.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Thorne</a>’s Inquisitors are openly tracking its fragments.
<br>Certain leyline flares and magical anomalies appear to align with cult activity — perhaps not by accident.
<br>Rumors say the cult is trying to reach Selune again, either physically or through planar magic, to return to the Eye’s root.
<br>Some fear they aim to create a new Eye elsewhere — one built not to contain, but to reveal.
]]></description><link>major-powers\shattered-sight.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Major Powers/Shattered Sight.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 06:02:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Red Howl]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>The Red Howl was a prototype lava-powered mobile siege engine, designed to traverse molten terrain and launch magma-laced payloads at enemy fortifications.<br>Tovar Ferrosyn envisioned it as a revolutionary war machine—a symbol of Dominion superiority, capable of overwhelming monsters and rival kingdoms alike.<br><br><br>
<br>During its first full-scale demonstration, the Red Howl overheated catastrophically.
<br>Its internal core collapsed under thermal imbalance, triggering a violent venting of molten payloads.
<br>Two test engineers died instantly. Several others suffered severe burns.
<br>The blast damaged the outer city walls near the proving ground.
<br>Tovar barely survived—he still bears burn scars
<br><br><br>
<br>The Ember Throne intervened, terminating the Red Howl Initiative for "reckless deployment of uncontrolled innovation."
<br>Tovar was barred from initiating new siegecraft projects without Tribunal oversight.
<br>Though he remains the official head of House Ferrosyn, his political influence was weakened, especially among conservative houses like <a data-href="House Keldros" href="houses\arken\house-keldros.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">House Keldros</a>.
<br><br><br>
<br>Among Ferrosyn loyalists, the Red Howl is remembered as a tragedy of ambition—a vision smothered by fear.
<br>Among Dominion officials, it stands as a dire warning: power without control invites destruction.
<br>Some whisper the core may have reacted to something buried beneath the proving grounds—a tremor not of heat, but of will.
]]></description><link>one-off-pages\red-howl.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">One off pages/Red Howl.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 21:40:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[✦ Vault of Elarion]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
“To understand the world, begin at its name.”
<br>A singular record, whispered through leyline, lore, and time.<br>
This vault holds the threads of a realm shaped by rift and relic, by oath and ruin.<br><br><br>→ <a data-href="🌍 The World of Elarion" href="🌍-the-world-of-elarion.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">🌍 The World of Elarion</a>]]></description><link>index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Index.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 04:26:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[🌍 The World of Elarion]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>A single-continent world with two distant islands, fractured kingdoms, magical secrets, and a growing threat from the north.<br><br><br><br>
<br>Type: Centralized monarchy
<br>Ruler: Queen Araleth VI
<br>Capital: Caer Thalor
<br>Magic: Strictly regulated; only licensed practitioners
<br>Military: Highly disciplined and loyal
<br>Nobility: Most noble houses are loyal to the queen
<br><br><br>
<br>Type: Alliance of free city-states
<br>Council Head: Lord Berrick of Myrhold
<br>Major Cities: Myrhold, Tarnath, Velmira, Cenwyn, Estrellan
<br>Magic: Lightly regulated, magic-users live freely
<br>Military: Independent militias and hired adventurers
<br><br><br>
<br>Type: Theocratic empire
<br>Ruler: Emperor Kavalh
<br>Capital: Varkhaz-Thul (surrounded by rivers of lava)
<br>Magic: Only divine and state-sanctioned arcane
<br>Known for: Master forges powered by volcanic flows
<br><br><br>
<br>
Type: Druidic confederation

<br>
Council: Council of Speakers

<br>
Magic: Natural and spiritual magic, tied to leylines

<br>
Known for: Deep forests, harmony with nature

<br>
<a data-href="Obelion" href="major-powers\obelion.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Obelion</a> floats above Valewind, strengthening the leyline beneath it.

<br><br><br>
<br>Type: Independent holy city-state
<br>Governance: Council of Halos
<br>Religion: Center of the Church that worships Saint Vivi
<br>Known for: The Perfect Barrier that repels evil
<br>The Barrier protects the entire north.
<br>Saint Vivi is revered as a martyr who died casting the Barrier.
<br><br><br>
<br>Type: Elven forest kingdom
<br>Ruler: Queen Liraethe Velyndor 
<br>Magic: Ancient, dream-bound, and song-based
<br>Culture: Reverent, quiet, rarely seen beyond the woods
<br><br><br><br>
<br>Type: Floating arcane citadel (Known as: The One True Tower)
<br>Governance: Archmage and Circle of Twelve
<br>Location: Mostly hovers above Valewind
<br>Known for: Research into barriers, leylines, and forgotten magic
<br>Obelion has discovered how to move the floating island, albeit slowly.
<br><br><br>
<br>HQ: Steelmark, an independent city not claimed by any kingdom
<br>Structure: Strict rank-based system:

<br>Porcelain, Copper, Bronze, Iron, Silver, Gold, Platinum, Mithril, Orichalcum, Adamantite
<br>Mithril and above require recommendation and legendary deeds


<br>Officially neutral and does not participate in wars.
<br><br><br><br>
<br>Former crescent-shaped island kingdom
<br>Now a ruined landmass overrun by monsters and rift-magic
<br>At its center stood the Eye of the World—once a trial site for a vessel meant to contain evil
<br>History
In the previous campaign, the players failed to complete the trial at the Eye. The ancient king who once absorbed evil was corrupted, causing the island’s collapse and unleashing chaos.
<br><br><br>
<br>
Location: Beyond the Titan’s Spine Mountains in the north

<br>
Believed to be a result of Selune’s collapse and planar rift magic

<br>
Now home to monsters, twisted magic, and aberrations

<br>
ᛚᚷᛞ ᛉᛒᛟᛝᛞᛃ ᛟᛁᚹᛁᛒᚠᚷᚢ ᛟᚦᛉ Barrier ᛡᛗᛚᛗᛋ ᛡᛉᛟᚢ safe.

<br><br><br>
<br>ᚺᛚᛁᛋᚺ ᛋᛟᛇᚠᛒᚷᛇ ᚠᛡᛗᚱᛇᛖᛇᚦᛠᛝᚱᚲᚷ ᛉᚦᛞᛡᛈᛇ
<br>ᚹᚨᛁᚾᛚᛟᚠ ᛝᚢᛠᚺ ᛋᚾᛃᛗᚠᛗᛈ ᚨᚹᛞ ᛚᚨᛡᛁᛇᚾ ᛉᛞ ᛟᛗᛚ ᛖᛡᛋᚨ ᛋᛗ
<br>ᛁᛈᛈᛏᛃ ᛚᛠᚨᛚᛗᛈᛞᛖᚺᛟ ᚱᚱᚱᛚᚹᛏᚲᚾᛉᚺ ᛡᛝᚺᚹᚠᛡᚱᚱ ᛟᚱ ᚠᛋᛗᛠᚾᛈᛃᛒ ᛠᚲᚹ ᚷᚨᛁᛈᛁᛒ
<br>ᛒᛞᚠᛞᚢᛃᛞᚢᛗᚹ ᛈᚷᛗᚦ ᛞᚨᚢᚲᛞ ᛖᛗᛒ ᚲᚺᛏᚷᚨᚺᚷ ᚲᚹᛝᛡ ᛇᛋᛝ ᚦᛉᛡᛡᚲᛗ ᚱᛚᛞᛖᛟᛁᛞᚱᚱᚦᛝᚦ ᛃᛋᚷᚱᚹᚦ
<br><br><br><br>
<br>Magic is rare. Only the Gifted can level up or cast spells.
<br>Healing magic is incredibly uncommon outside of the Church, elves, and adventurers.
<br>Potions only work for the Gifted.
<br><br>
<br>Magic items (wands, weapons, tools, etc.) can be used by anyone, even those without the Gift.
<br>This makes enchanted tools and relics incredibly valuable, especially to nobles, military forces, and wealthy tradesfolk. 
<br>Most magic tools are crafted with specific intent—many require training, activation rituals, or command words passed down through bloodlines or guilds.
<br>Powerful artifacts still require attunement by a Gifted soul.
<br><br><br>
“The world isn’t breaking. It’s remembering.”<br>
— Unknown bard, one night before vanishing near the Shoreline
<br><br><br>In recent years, strange phenomena have begun to surface across the land—glimmering distortions, patches of withered earth, places where time moves oddly. Some call them rifts. Others whisper of cracks in the world.<br>No one knows their true origin.<br>
<br>Scholars speculate they may be remnants of ancient magic.
<br>Some blame the fall of Selune, the lost island that once held the Eye of the World.
<br>Others claim the world is simply unraveling—slowly, and with purpose.
<br><br><br>
<br>Rifts appear in places of old power: forgotten ruins, ancient battlefields, leyline nexuses, or cursed groves.
<br>They are often harmless to observe, though deeply unsettling:  

<br>Colors shift,  
<br>Sound warps,  
<br>Gravity misbehaves.


<br>Magic acts unpredictably near them.<br>
Spells might flare, fizzle, or echo back twisted versions of themselves.
<br>Most rifts attract strange creatures. Others do nothing—for years.
<br>Tales persist of voices heard through rifts—familiar, dead, or never known.
<br><br><br>
<br>The Church:

<br>Cautious and divided. Some clergy call rifts divine trials; others fear corruption.


<br>The Adventurer’s Guild:

<br>Monitors and classifies rift zones.
<br>Bounties exist for rift investigation, recovery, or neutralization.


<br>The Magic Tower of Obelion:

<br>Publicly silent.
<br>Rumored to secretly observe, catalog, and experiment with rifts.


<br>Common Folk:

<br>Avoid rifts at all costs.
<br>Build shrines, wards, or stone circles nearby—just in case.


<br><br><br><a data-href="Cenwyn" href="houses\dravandor\cenwyn.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Cenwyn</a><br>
A rural city where sudden auroras and eerie rainfall are becoming common.<br>
Locals report strange dreams, missing livestock, and lights in the woods.<br>Obsidian Shoreline<br>
An abandoned port town where a rift shimmers offshore.<br>
Fishermen claim something watches from the sea floor.<br>The Withered Hollow<br>
A once-lush grove now completely dead.<br>
No birds sing, and tools rust overnight when left in the clearing.<br><br><br>
<br>Passing through a rift may change a person—body or soul.
<br>Artifacts found near rifts sometimes exhibit sentience or warped magic.
<br>Some bards sing of a time before the rifts, when the world was whole.<br>
And how that world might ᛝᛁᛞᚢᛈᛏ ᚺᚦ ᛏᚷᚷᚨᛞᚠᚨᚷᛋ ᚦᛞ ᚹᛗᚹ ᚷᛠᛖᚦᚾ ᚷᚱᛟᛖᛃ
]]></description><link>🌍-the-world-of-elarion.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">🌍 The World of Elarion.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 06:13:52 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>